I'm gonna tell my Bernard of you!!
من اين کارت رو به برنارد مييم
You fuckin' dead!
ميکشتت
Oi! Come back 'ere, you!
هوي! تو! بررد اينجا
Ronnie !
روني
Geroff that couch and come out 'ere!
ول کن اون تخت رو، بدو بيا اينجا
Oh, shit! Sorry, I didn't see you there.
اوه شرمنده، نديدمت
Do you live 'ere?
اينجا زندي ميکني؟
Yeah, I do unfortunately.
آره، متاسفانه همينطوه
Do you know Louise Clancy ?
لوئيس کلانسي رو ميشناسي؟
Yeah. Are you friend of hers?
آره. تو دوستش هستي؟
Know where she is?
ميدوني کجاست؟
She's at work
سر کاره
What time does she get back?
کي بر ميرده؟
Dunno. About seven or something
نميدونم. حدود ساعت هفت
Fuckin' hell !
لعنتي
D'you wanna come in for a cuppa tea?
ميخواي بياي تو، يه فنجون اي بخوري؟
Is it alright with you, love?
براي تو موردي نداره عزيزم؟
It's just, you know, cold
ميدوني، آخه هوا سرده
Listen, have you got anything for a headache?
يزي براي سردرد داري؟
Ah, yeah, we 'ave as it 'appens
آره، اتفاقا داريم
You know, like a monkey-wrench or somethin'
يک يزي که حالم رو جا بياره
What's all this about?
اينا ديه يه؟
Oh yeah, that's Sandra, that is
اينا، برا ساندراست
Hallo, Sandra.
سلام ساندرا
This is 'er place
اينجا برا اونه
She's a fuckin' nurse
يه رستاره به دردنخوره
That's 'er idea of interior design
اين ايده ي طراحي داخليشه
Oh yeah - it's a skeletion
آره - اسکلته
And this is 'er cocktail cabinet, an' all
اين هم کابينت خرت و رت هاشه
There you go, that should do it
خودشه، اين بايد به دردت بخوره
No, it's too big
نه، اين خيلي بزره
D'you want a cuppa tea?
يک ليوان اي ميخوري؟
So are you Louise's boyfriend?
س تو دوست سر لوئيسي؟
No.
نه
Oh, right. What, you're just like a mate?
آهان. يه جور ارتنري؟
Primate
يشوا
You must be the missing link then
س تو بايد حلقه ي مفقوده باشي
Yeah, that's me
آره، خودمم
You're not gonna tell me your name?
نميخواي اسمت رو بهم بي؟
No.
نه
I'm not gonna tell you mine neither
خب، س منم مال خودم رو نميم
All right, we'll be strangers
باشه، غريبه مي مونيم
- I see your boomerang came back then, love - It's not my fuckin' boomerang
ميبينم که بوم رنت برشته عزيزم اين بوم رن من نيست
What about the old diminishing pachyderm formation there?
اون حيوون وست کلفتِ رو به انقراض ي؟
No, that's all Sandra's collection
نه، همش کلکسيون ساندراست
She's in Zimbabwe at the moment.
اون الان توي زيمباوست
And fuck knows what she's gonna bring back from there
و هيکس نميدونه ي قراره از اونجا بياره
Pellagra or hepatitis B or something.
لارا، هاتيت ب، يزي تو اين مايه ها که نداري؟
She's with her boyfriend
اون با دوست سرشه
So how is Louise?
خب، لوئيس طوره؟
I dunno. I don't know 'er as well as you.
نميدونم من به اندازه ي تو نميشناسمش
D'you get on with 'er?
باهاش رابطه داري؟
We've been out a couple o' times.
جند بار با هم رفتيم بيرون
Does she like you?
اون دوستت داره؟
I dunno - you'd better ask 'er.
نميدونم، بهتره از خودش برسي
Most people don't.
اکثر مردم دوستم ندارن
Do you find she's at all jealous of you?
فکر ميکني اون هميشه بهت حسودي ميکنه؟
So, I dunno, would you describe yourself as a happy little person?
خب، نميدونم، تو خودت رو يه آدم شاد توصيف ميکني؟
Yeah, I'm the life and soul
آره، من جوهره ي هستي ام
Have you ever thought, right
تا حالا فکر کردي
I mean, you don't know,
منظورم اينه که، تو نميدوني
but you may already 'ave had
ولي شايد الان بهترين
the happiest moment in your whole fuckin' life
لحظه ي زنديت رو داري تجربه ميکني
and all you've got to look forward to is sickness
و تمام يزهايي که ميتوني براشون انتظار بکشي، بيماري
and purgatory?
و روز برزخه؟
Oh, shit!
اوه
Well, I just live from day to day, meself.
خب، من شخصا با روزمري زندي ميکنم
I tend to skip a day now and again - you know what I mean?
من تمايل دارم امروز رو رد کنم و دوباره...، مي فهمي ي ميم؟
I used to be a werewolf,
من قبلا ورولف (شخصي در افسانه ها که تبديل به ر شده بود) بودم
- But I'm all right noowwww!! - Oh, fuckin' 'ell !!
ولي الان خيلي خوووووووبم اوه، لعنتي
I bet they're 'appy, eh?
من شرط ميبندم اونا خوشحالن، نظرت يه؟
All they gotta do is sit round, howlin' at the moon.
تنها کاري که بايد بکنن اينه که دور هم جمع بشن و رو به ماه زوزه بکشن
It's better than standin' on the cheesy fuckin' thing. Know what I mean?
بهتر از اينه که وقتشون رو صرف يزهاي مزخرف کنن، ميفهمي ي ميم؟
I mean, tossin' all these satellites and shuttles out into the cosmos -
مثلا رتاب اين همه ماهواره و شاتل به فضا
what do they think they're gonna find up there that they can't find down 'ere?
فکر ميکنن اون بالا ي ميتونن يدا کنن، که اين ايين نميتونن؟
They think if they piss high enough,
فکر ميکنن اه به اندازه ي کافي نده وزي کنن
they're gonna come across the monkey with the beard and the crap ideas,
ممکنه بر بخورن به ميمون با ريش و ايده هاي مزخرف
and it's like, 'Oh! There you are Captain!
بعد مثلا مين، اوه کايتان! س شما اون جا هستين
I mean , are you busy, because I've got a few fundamental questions for you!'
مثلا مين؛ شما سرتون شلوغه؟ من از شما سوالات بنيادين دارم
Are you with me?
حواست با منه؟
Yeah, 'cos let's face it, right, what are rockets?
آره، بيا بهش فکر کنيم. اصلا راکت يه؟
I mean, they're just, big metal pricks!
منظورم اينه که اونا فقط يه تيکه آهن اره هستن
You know, I mean, the bastards aren't satisfied with fuckin' the earth up -
منظورم اينه که حرومزاده ها به زمين قانع نيستن
they've gotta fuck space an' all.
انار حتما بايد به فضا هم ند بزنن
Will you tell me something, love?
يه يزي رو به من ميي عزيزم؟
Are you aware of the effect you have on the average
آيا تو از تاثيري که به طور متوسط روي
mammalian, Mancunian,
ستانداران، منستري ها
X-Y-ly-chromosome, slavering, lusty male member
کروموزوم هاي ايکس و ايري، برده داري و مردان شهوتي داري
of the species?
مطلعي؟
- Yeah - I thought so.
آره فکرش رو ميکردم
Would you like to have dinner with me tonight?
دوست داري امشب با من شام بخوري؟
No !
نه
Do you think women like being raped?
فکر ميکني زنها دوست دارن مورد تجاوز قرار بيرن؟
You talk a lot, don't you?
خيلي حرف ميزني، مه نه؟
Do you like japanese food?
تو غذاي ژاني دوست داري؟
Look, I've told you - I'm not interested.
ببين، يک دفعه بهت فتم، علاقه اي ندارم
All right?
باشه؟
Could I have that a touch harder, please?
ميشه محکم تر ماساژ بدي، لطفا؟
All right? Enjoyin' yourself, are you?
خب، خوشي با خودت؟
I'm 'aving a great time, actually
در واقع خيلي داره به من خوش ميذره
Bloody 'ell
لعنتي
Oh, friendly!
اوه، ه مهربون
What are you doin' 'ere? You look like shit.
تو اينجا يکار ميکني؟ شبيه ه شدي
Just trying to blend in
داشتم سعي ميکردم خودم رو با محيط يرامون
with the surroundings
وفق بدم
Halitosis, halitosis, halitosis!
بوندو، بوندو، بوندو
Can't believe you're 'ere
باورم نميشه که تو اينجايي
I'm not 'ere.
من اينجا نيستم
I'll tell you what, it's a crackin' place you've got, love.
خونه ي خيلي خوبي داري عزيزم
Good. I'm glad you like it.
خوبه. خوشحالم دوسش داري
No, I was been sarcastic.
نه، داشتم طعنه ميزدم
Why didn't you tell me you were comin'? I would a' met you off the train.
را به من نفتي که داري مياي؟ ميخواستم وقتي از قطار ياده ميشي ببينمت
I didn't come on the fuckin' train.
من با قطار نيومدم
- Off the bus, then. - I didn't come on the bus either.
از اتوبوس خب با اتوبوس هم نيومدم
So 'ow did you get 'ere then?
خب س طوري اومدي اينجا؟
Well, basically, there was this little dot, right? And the dot went bang,
خب، به سادي! اول يک نقطه بود درست؟ بعد نقطه منفجر شد
and the bang expanded,
و انفجار سترش يدا کرد
energy formed into matter, matter cooled, matter lived, the amoeba to fish, the fish to fowl, the fowl to frog, the frog to mammal
انرژي تبديل شد به ماده، ماده سرد شد، ماده زندي کرد تک سلولي به ماهي، ماهي به مرغ مرغ به وزغ، وزغ به ستاندار
the mammal to monkey, the monkey to man.
ستاندار به ميمون، ميمون به انسان
Amo, amas, amat, quid pro quo, memento mori,
من عاشقم، تو عاشقي، اون عاشقه اين به اون در، يادت باشه ميميري
ad infinitum, sprinkle on a little bit of grated cheese and leave under the grill till Doomsday.
براي هميشه، يکم آب باش روي يک تکه نير و بذارش زير باربيکيو، تا روز قيامت
I see you 'aven't changed.
ميبينم که تغييري نکردي
'e's a fuckin' genius, this geezer!
واقعا نابغه است اين يارو
I take it you've met my wicky-wacky friend Sophie?
ميبينم که رفيق فابريکت رو يدا کردي، سوفي؟
No, actually, we 'aven't been formally introduced, 'ave we, love?
نه، در واقع ما رسما به هم معرفي نشديم. درست نميم عزيزم؟
No, we've been sat 'ere in
نه، ما اين جا نشسته بوديم
embarassin' silence all afternoon.
تمام بعد از ظهر رو از رودربايستي در سکوت ذرونديم
So , 'ow are you?
خب، تو طوري؟
Peachy-creamy.
فوق العاده
Are you really? I'm very pleased.
جدا؟ خيلي خوشحالم
So how's, um, work?
خب، کار و بار طوره؟
It's all right.
رو به راهه
Is it everything you hoped it would be?
همه ي همونطوريه که دوست داشتي باشه؟
What did you hope it would be?
دوست داشتي طوري باشه؟
I'm sorry - did you get that?
ببخشيد، تو فهميدي ي شد؟
It's everything she hoped it would be,
همه ي همونطوريه که دوست داشت باشه
but she doesn't fuckin' know what she hoped it would be!
ولي اون حتي نميدونه که دوست داشت طوري باشه
Oh, and by the way. Thank you for this!
اوه، و در هر صورت، براي اين ازت متشکرم
I mean, are you tekkin' the piss,
منظورم اينه که، اينجا داري ميشاشي؟
or what?
ي کار ميکني؟
'So, Johnny... My address is'
خب، جاني... آدرس من اينه
I'm touched.
من متاثر شدم
- Why 'ave you come? - Oh, can you tell from there?
را اومدي؟ تو از اونجا ميتوني حدس بزني؟
D'you want a cup o'tea?
يک فنجون اي ميخواي؟
I'd love a cup o'tea. You're fuckin'
من عاشق يک فنجون ايم. تو واقعا
generous, you cockerneys, aren't yer?
سخاوتمندي، مه نه؟
Yeah. Ta.
آره، ممنون
'ow's yer mam?
مامانت طوره؟
Fine. 'ow's yours? Still pullin' pints?
خوبه، مال تو ي؟ هنوز نفس ميکشه؟
She's dead. She's still a good fuck, though.
اون مرده، اره هنوز کُس خوبيه
I mean the rates are a bit extortionate, but I do get a discount, what with being the son and everything.
منظورم اينه که نرخ ها الان يکم زياد شده ولي من تخفيف مييرم. بالاخره سري فتن
Apparently, right, you shouldn't stick
معلومه، تو نبايد يزي رو که توي
anything up your cunt
دهنت نميره
you can't put in your mouth.
تو کُست بکني
Give us that mug.
اون ليوان رو بده به من
Can I try your coat on, Johnny?
ميتونم کتت رو بوشم جاني؟
So what you've been up to? 'ave you seen anybody?
خب، تو ي کار کردي؟ کسي رو ديدي؟
Have you seen anybody?
تو کسي رو ديدي؟
Have you spoken to anybody from Manchester?
تو با کسي از منستر صحبت کردي؟
Yeah, I've phoned June a couple o' times.
آره، من به ژون دو بار تلفن زدم
And was June interested in what you had to say?
و ژون به يزي که ميخواستي بي علاقه مند بود؟
Fuckin' hell. I've seen more life in an open grave. Come on!!
من توي قبر احساس زندي بيشتري ميکنم، بي خيال
- What? - What?! I mean, you don't not seem very pleased to see me.
يه؟ يه؟! منظورم اينه که به نظر ميرسه تو از ديدن من خيلي خوشحال نيستي
I am pleased to see you!
من از ديدنت خوشحالم
Are you too good for us? Now you've got yourself a posh job in a big 'shitty'?
تو خيلي به ما خوبي ميکني؟ حالا يه شغل شيک تو يه سدوني يرت اومده؟
I mean, me an''her
منظورم اين که، من و اون
- are on the fuckin' dole, aren't we? - Right!
داريم با کمک حق بيمه ي ايام بيکاري زندي ميکنيم، نه؟ درسته
And you're a carrier girl - are you happy with that? Are you sure?
و تو يک دختر حمالي؛ از اين خوشحالي؟ مطمئني؟
I'm delighted
من خوشحالم
D'you want some o' this,
يکم از اين ميخواي؟
Johnny ?
جاني؟
Fuckin' 'ell love, what're you trying to do to me?
اوه لعنتي، داري سعي ميکني من رو معتاد کني؟
Right, well,
خب س
I'm going up to me room. D'you want to see it, Johnny?
من ميرم بالا تو اتاقم. ميخواي ببينيش جاني؟
Is it worth the bother?
ارزشش رو داره که به خودم زحمت بدم؟
Is there anything worth seein'?
جيزي اونجا هست که ارزش ديدن داشته باشه؟
Why don't you come and find out? It's not very far.
را خودت نمياي ببيني؟ خيلي دور نيست
I'm sorry about this.
عذر ميخوام
Move! Move!
تکون بخور، تکون بخور
Where are you?
کجايي؟
I'm in 'ere.
من اينجام
Oh, it's de-lovely.
اوه. دوست داشتنيه
I see you've got a ceiling at the top with a floor on the lower level,
اينطور که يداست بالا يه سقف داري و ايين تر هم يه کف
and a wall at either side.
و در هر سمت يه ديوار
And only a single bed. Sad, really
و فقط يه تخت يکنفره. ه بد
You've got wonderful breasts
تو ستونهاي خارق العاده اي داري
Don't you mean tits?
منظورت ممه نيست؟
Are they both of the same size,
هر جفتشون يک اندازن؟
or is one bigger than the other?
يا يکي بزرتر از اون يکيه؟
I don't know. Do you want to weigh them?
نميدونم. ميخواي وزنشون کني؟
Is that a proposition?
اين يه يشنهاده؟
No, it's a threat.
نه، يه تهديده
Are you rich?
تو ثروتمندي؟
- Life is for enjoying. - What's about family,
زندي براي لذت بردنه خانواده ي؟
have you got any brothers or sisters?
خواهر و برادر داري؟
I try not to remember.
سعي ميکنم به ياد نيارم
You are sexually
تو از لحاظ جنسي
frustrated, aren't you?
عقيمي؟ اينطور نيست؟
- What's funny? - Are you a feminist?
ه بامزه؟ تو فمينيستي؟
- Do you like fucking? - Do you like wanking?
تو اييدن رو دست داري؟ تو جلق زدن رو دوست داري؟
Not on my own, no.
نه براي خودم
That's a very ornithological mutilation you've got here, love.
That's a very ornithological mutilation you've got here, love.
That's my tribal initiation
اين از تشريفات قبيله اي منه
It is really?
واقعا؟
That was fuckin' athletic, that was.
حرکتت جدا ورزشکارانه بود
I think I've ruptured my chakras.
فکر کنم اکرام رو اره کردم
Is there an instruction manual for this garb?
اين لباس، دستورالعمل هم داره؟
No, it's an intelligence test.
نه، تست هوشه
Well what is this? A granny, a sheepshank,
اين يه؟ يک ره راست، يا يک ره موقت
or the infamous round-turn and two half-hitches,
يا اون ريه مزخرفِ بويه؟
as mentioned in the Book of Ezekiel?
همون که تو کتاب حزقيل ذکر شده؟
Have you finished?
تموم شد؟
I've hardly fuckin' begun.
تازه با بدختي شروع کردم
It's just that I think I'm gonna get into difficulties when I read the hippy-shit up here, you know what I mean?
فکر کنم که من هر وقت مزخرفات هيي ها رو ميخونم توي مخمصه مي افتم، ميفهمي ي ميم؟
Yeah, well, you've tried the stairs.
آره خب، تو از له اومدي
I think we should take the escalator.
فکر کنم بهتر باشه از له برقي استفاده کنيم
Simple really. So's this.
به همين سادي خب، اينه
Oh. Thanks for the mammaries.
اوه، ممنون ممنون از ممه
Could you ask her to order me a taxi,
ميشه لطفا ازش بخواي براي من يک تاکسي
please?
خبر کنه؟
This is terribly disappointing
واقعا نااميد کننده است
You don't like rejection, do you,
تو (نه) شنيدن رو که دوست نداري؟ داري جرمي؟
- Jeremy? - Could we have a taxi, please?
ميشه لطفا براي ما يک تاکسي خبر کني؟
No problem, sir.
مشکلي نداره قربان
It's really cozy, this.
اينجا واقعا دنجه
Will you let me come again, Jerry?
اجازه ميدي بعدا دوباره بيام جري؟
You're dead handsome, you know.
تو خيلي خوشتيي، ميدوني؟
What work d'you do?
شغلت يه؟
I'm a dancer, actually.
من راستش رو بخواي رقاصم
Do you want to know me name?
ميخواي اسم من رو بدوني؟
It's Giselle.
ژيسل
Are you married?
تو متاهلي؟
Wha' ?
يه؟
Kiss me.
بوس بده
Don't, it's yucky! Get it off!
نکن، زشته! ورش دار
Are you glad I came?
خوشحالي از اومدنم؟
What are you doin'? Get off me!!
ي کار ميکني؟ نکن
You're hurting me!
داري بهم آسيب ميرسوني
Have you ever thought of committing
تا حالا فکر کردي که
suicide?
خودکشي کني؟
I'm going to commit suicide.
من ميخوام خودکشي کنم
on my fortieth birthday.
در هلمين سال تولدم
If I'm still around.
اه تا اون موقع هنوز زنده بودم
- Why? - I don't want to be old.
را؟ نميخوام ير بشم
Do you?
تو ميخواي؟
Oh. 'Ave a fag
اوه، سيار برداشتي؟
Yeah. Thanks, I will
آره، ممنون
What you're readin'?
ي ميخوني؟
Would you stop fuckin' about and fidgetin' in my peripherals -
ميشه به اين وول خوردن هات در اطراف من خاتمه بدي؟
I'm trying to concentrate.
دارم سعي ميکنم تمرکز کنم
She's got a very little waist, Sophie, an't she?
اون کمر باريکي داره، سوفي، اينطور نيست؟
She's got little tits an' all
و ممه هاي کويک
Are you not cold?
تو سردت نيست؟
- I'm reading about the Butterfly Effect. - What's the Butterfly Effect?
من دارم راجع به اثر شارکي مطالعه ميکنم ي هست اين اثر شارکي؟
Every time a butterfly flaps its wings in Tokyo,
هر بار که يک شارک در توکيو بالهاش رو به هم بزنه
this old granny in Salford gets a bilious attack..
يک مادر بزر، توي سالفرد حمله ي صفراوي بهش دست ميده
What happens if a butterfly flaps it's wings in Salford?
اه تو سالفرد بالهاش رو به هم بزنه ه اتفاقي مي افته؟
That's not the point.
مسئله اين نيست
Oh, is it not?
اوه؟ اين نيست؟
What are you doin' in London, Johnny?
توي لندن يکار ميکني جاني؟
What are you doin' in London?
تو توي لندن ي کار ميکني؟
I've told you what I'm doin' in London.
بهت فتم که من توي لندن ي کارم ميکنم
You've told me nothing.
تو هيي به من نفتي
The last time I saw you,
آخرين باري که ديدمت بهت فتم
- I told you - - Fuckin' hell! Were you born irritatin'?
لعنتي! تو ذاتا مزاحم به دنيا اومدي؟
What you came downstairs for anyway?
اصلا براي ي اومدي ايين؟
I fell asleep with the window open. I was cold. I came down.
با نجره ي باز خوابم برده بود. سردم بود. اومدم ايين
I 'ad to pee, I've made some tea, I'm 'ere, all right?
بايد ميشاشيدم، ايي درست کردم، الان هم اينجام، حله؟
What's that? The greatest story ever told?
اين يه؟ بهترين داستاني که تا حالا فته شده؟
I live 'ere
من اينجا زندي ميکنم
So what 'appened? Were you bored
خب ي شد؟ تو خسته شدي
in Manchester?
از منستر؟
Was I bored? No I wasn't fuckin' bored.
من خسته شدم؟ نه من عمرا خسته نشدم
I'm never bored. That's the trouble with everybody - you're all so bored.
من هرز خسته نشدم. همه اين مشکل رو دارن شما همه تون خسته اين
You've 'ad nature explained to you and you're bored with it.
شما طبيعت رو دارين که باهاتون حرف ميزنه و ازش خسته اين
You've 'ad the living body explained to you and you're bored with it,
شما يک بدن زنده دارين که باهاتون حرف ميزنه
You've had the universe explained to you and you're bored with it.
شما جهان رو دارين که باهاتون حرف ميزنه و ازش خسته اين
So now you just want cheap thrills and like plenty of 'em and it dun't matter
فقط دنبال يه سري ماجرا هاي ي هستين مثل بقيه شون و اين مهم نيست که
'ow tawdry or vacuous they are as long as it's new, as long as it's new,
قدر اين مسائل مزخرف و وه تا وقتي که جديده، تا وقتي که جديده
as long as it flashes and fuckin' bleeps in forty fuckin' different colors.
تا وقتي که برق ميزنه و تو هل تا رن مختلف شمک ميزنه
Well, whatever else you can say about me, I'm not fuckin' bored!
خب، هر يزي که بخواي ميتوني راجع به من بي من خسته نيستم
Yeah, all right.
خوب، باشه
So 'ow's it all goin' for you?
خب، تو راجع به اينا ي فکر ميکني؟
It's a bit borin', actually.
خسته کننده بود در واقع
Are you not enjoyin' yourself?
تو خوش نميذروني؟
Have you made many friends?
رفقاي زيادي يدا کردي؟
No
نه
'Ave you got, erm, a goblet or something, because me heart's bleedin'.
يه يلاسي يزي داري، ون من قلبم جريحه دار شده
When you goin' back to Manchester?
کي بر ميردي به منستر؟
I'm not going back
من بر نمي ردم
- Why not? - You know why not
را نه؟ تو ميدوني را
Do I?
ميدونم؟
I thought you said you never wanted to see me again
من فکر کنم تو فتي که ديه نميخواي من رو ببيني
I don't want to ever see you again, so why you just don't fuck off back upstairs?
من ديه هي وقت نميخوام تو رو ببينم س را ورت رو م نميکني بالا؟
Why are you such a bastard, Johnny?
را اينقدر حرومزاده اي جاني؟
- Monkey see, monkey do. - And what does that mean?
ميمون ميبينه، ميمون انجام ميده و معني اين يه؟
Oh, this fuckin' cough.
اوه، اين سرفه ي لعنتي
A butterfly must'ave flapped it's wings.
احتمالا يه شارک بالهاش رو به هم زده
So, have you got to get up for work now, yeah?
خب الان وقتيه که براي کار از خواب بلند ميشدي؟
No. It's too early.
نه، خيلي زوده
I'm going back to bed.
بر ميردم به تختخواب
So is she a - a Buddhist or something, this nurse?
اين رستاره بودايي موداييه؟
No, she's a Catholic.
نه، کاتوليکه
What's she doin' with the old fat chap in the house, then?
س با اين مرد اق قديمي تو خونش ي کار داره؟
Dunno, I think she fancies him or somethin'.
نميدونم، فکر کنم بهش علاقه منده
Louise is a Catholic, did you know that?
لوئيس يک کاتوليکه، ميدونستي؟
She's not, is she?
نه، واقعا؟
Oh, fuckin' hell!
اوه، لعنتي
You know what frightens me about the human body?
تو ميدوني ي در مورد بدن انسان من رو ميترسونه؟
What?
ي؟
Well, it's like the most sophisticated mechanism in the entire universe,
خب، به نظر مياد که ييده ترين مکانيسم در کل دنيا رو داشته باشه
and yet it's so fuckin' quiet, in't it?
و همنان کاملا ساکته. اينطور نيست؟
know what I mean?
ميفهمي ي ميم؟
Dunno... Mine makes enough noise.
نميدونم، برا من به اندازه ي کافي سر و صدا ميکنه
It's like this wet, pink factory.
مثل اين کارخونه ي خيس صورتي
What the fuck are they makin' in there? I mean what's the product?
ه آشغالي دارن اونتو درست ميکنن؟ منظورم اينه که محصولشون يه؟
You never see no delivery trucks comin' or goin', do you?
تو هي وقت کاميون هاي حمل بار رو نميبيني
I could've been a doctor.
من ميتونستم زشک بشم
D'you wanna examine me?
ميخواي من رو معاينه کني؟
You don't believe me, do you?
تو حرف من رو باور نمي کني، نه؟
I believe everything you say.
من هر ي تو بي باور ميکنم
I've got A-level Psychology.
من مدرک درجه آ روانشناسي دارم
You 'aven't!
نه بابا
"Resolve is never stronger
"Resolve is never stronger
than in the morning after the night it was never weaker".
than in the morning after the night it was never weaker".
What d'you think of that?
نظرت راجع به اين يه؟
It's a load of bollocks.
مزخرفه
I thought of that.
فکرش رو ميکردم
D'you not agree with it?
تو با اين موافق نيستي؟
Dunno
نمي دونم
Yeah, well, that's 'cos you weren't fuckin' listening, were you?
آره؛ خب، به خاطر اين که تو اصلا وش نميکني، درسته؟
What's this? A test or somethin'?
اين حرف ها يعني ي؟ داري امتحانم ميکني؟
Don't! Stop it!
نکن! بسه
Just pack it in! Stop it!
فقط بيا! نکن
Stop buggering about!
کرم نريز
You could get me a watch, Johnny
ميشه برا من يک ساعت بيري جاني؟
Will you just keep still?!
آروم نمييري؟
Look, you could get me a watch
ببين، ميشه يک ساعت برا من بيري
I'm not gonna get you a watch - you don't want a fuckin' watch!!
من برات ساعت نمييرم، تو ساعت لازم نداري
I really like you, Johnny.
من خيلي دوستت دارم جاني
You don't know me.
تو من رو نميشناسي
I think I do.
فکر کنم بشناسم
You don't fuckin' -
تو حتي نميدوني
- ..know me! - Oh, shit!
من کيم اوه، لعنتي
- D'you still like me? - I love you.
تو هنوز من رو دوست داري؟ من عاشقتم
- What? - I'm in love with you, Johnny.
ي؟ من عاشقتم جاني
Don't laught - I'm serious, uh!
نخند، جدي ميم
I understand you Johnny, I do.
درکت ميکنم جاني، درکت ميکنم
Ta-ra, Mr. Halpern.
به سلامت آقاي هالرن
What's the matter? What's going on?
ي شده؟ اينجا ه خبره؟
Fucked if I know.
واقعا نميدونم
I'm too old for all this.
من خيلي براي اين يزها ير شدم
Why don't we go out ? Go for a drink or somethin'?
را نمياي بريم بيرون؟ يک نوشيدني اي، يزي بخوريم
Why don't you fuckin' go out?
را تو ورت رو م نميکني؟ برو يک نوشيدني اي، يزي بخور
'Cos I wanna go with you!
براي اينکه من ميخوام با تو برم
Is this good?
اين خوبه؟
What are you doin'? Where are you goin'?
ي کار داري ميکني؟ کجا داري ميري؟
I'm cold!
سردمه
- Johnny, I just - - Fuck off!
جاني، من فقط مشو
Fuckin' hell! D'you ever get the feelin' that you're bein' followed?
لعنتي! تا حالا اين حس رو داشتي که دارن تعقيبت ميکنن؟
Look, will you just leave me alone - give me a bit of room or somethin'?
ببين، ميشه فقط من رو تنها بذاري؟ يکم جا به من بده
Fuckin' hell!
لعنتي
What's all that about? What you're playing at?
اين کارها يعني ي؟ اين ه بازييه که در آوردي؟
- Where are you going, Johnny? - Off my head.
کجا ميري جاني؟ ميرم به درک
- I'm comin' with you. - No, you're not.
منم با تو ميام نه، تو اين کار رو نميکني
- I wanna come with you! - I don't want to you fuckin' come with me!
من ميخوام باهات بيام من هي علاقه اي ندارم که تو با من بياي
Are you coming back?
برميردي؟
What the fuck for?
که ي بشه؟
Maggie !
مي
You all right there, chief?
حالتون خوبه جناب؟
'Ave you lost somebody?
کسي رو م کردي؟
Are you looking for somebody?
دنبال کسي ميردي؟
Fuck off, cunt!!
خفه شو، اقال
Got a fag?
سيار داري؟
- Yes, thanks. - Uh?
آره ممنون ها؟
- Yes, I've got one. - Giz one.
آره، يکي دارم رد کن بياد
- Please. - Wha'?
لطفا هان؟
Say please.
بو لطفا
Just fuckin' giz one. Come on, mister!
يدونه رد کن بياد، زود باش آقا
You've got a lovely way about you - 'as anybody ever told you that?
تو رفتار جالبي داري، کسي تا حالا اين رو بهت فته؟
'Thank you. That's all right.'
متشکرم. قابلي نداشت
Maggie !
مي
She's gone, mate!
اون رفته رفيق
Those days are over.
اون روزها ديه تموم شده
Have you seen a lassie wanderin' aboot here?
تو يک دخترکي رو نديدي اين اطراف بلکه؟
What?
ي؟
A lassie. Black hair, blue jeans.
يک دخترک. موهاي سياه، جين آبي
I saw a little Border collie padding off down there towards a fire.
من يک بردر کولي(نوعي س) کوولو ديدم که داشت اون ايين به سمت آتيش راه ميرفت
Where?
کجا؟
'Ave you lost your bird or somethin'?
رفيقه ات رو م کردي؟
Aye. Have you've seen her? Black hair?
آره. تو نديديش؟ موهاي سياه؟
- No - Fuckin' hell! Stupid fuckin' cunt's gone
نه لعنتي! جنده ي ابله ذاشته رفته
and got lost.
و يداش نيست
- You're from Scotland? - Uh?
تو از اسکاتلند اومدي؟ ها؟
- Are you scots? - Aye.
اسکاتلندي هستي؟ آره
What's it like up there?
اون طرف ها ه جوريه؟
Fuckin' shite! I'll kick her fanny in.
لعنتي کونش ميذارم
- D'you dream in Scotch? - Uh?
تو به اسکاتلندي خواب ميبيني؟ ها؟
Like, dream about sporran-clad, caber-tossin'
Like, dream about sporran-clad, caber-tossin'
haggis, gallopin' over porridge-covered glens?
haggis, gallopin' over porridge-covered glens?
Talking shite.
کس نو
Yeah, well, I sent off for one of those Linguaphone packages, 'Talk Shite in a Fortnight' -
خب من با اين بسته هاي آموزش زبان دارم کار ميکنم دو هفته است که دارم کسشعر ميشنوم
't's all goin' very well. I haven't quite got the hang of the transitive verbs yet, but -
همه يز خوب يش ميره. منتها من هنوز تو زمينه ي افعال متعدي خيلي خوب نشدم، ولي
Will you fuckin' shut it, eh?!
خفه خون ميري يا نه؟
- What you're doing down here? - Eh?
اينجا ي کار ميکني؟ ها؟
Why are you here in London, O Bodhidharma?
برا ي اومدي لندن؟
Put my old man in hospital.
بابام رو ذاشتم بيمارستان
- Your dad? - Ah.
بابات؟ آره
- 'Ow did you do that, then? - Cracked 'im on the nut wi' a poker.
ي کارش کرده بودي؟ با سيخ زده بودم تو سرش
- What for? - 'E was fuckin' asking for it!
را؟ خودش ازم خواست
So what, is 'e in a bad way?
که ي، الان حالش بده؟
Fuckin' right. He's 'alf dead.
آره. نيم جونه
What does you mam think about it?
مامانت ه حسي داره؟
She's off 'er fuckin' nut.
کله ي خودش رو بريد
So you're like on the run, yeah?
مثل اينکه داري در ميري، درسته؟
- Aye. - Yeah, me too.
آره منم همينطور
Yeah? The cops after you? Yeah?
ها؟ ليس دنبالته؟ آره؟
- Can you tell me something', Jock. - Uh?
ميتوني يه يزي رو به من بي، اسکاتلندي؟ ها؟
What's all that about?
اينا براي يه؟
That. The old Highland fling, there. D'you know you're doing that?
همين رقص قديميه اسکاتلندي تو خودت نميفهمي که اين کار رو ميکني؟
- What? - That, you know - 'And now for my next tic...'. That.
ي؟ همين، ميفهمي؟... و حالا تيک بعدي.... همين
Look, it, it just happened again - I'm not imaginin' it.
ناه، دوباره کرد، باورم نميشه
Fuck off, eh?
مشو
D'you do that in a sack with the old tic, spit, 'Eh, Maggie!'?
توي تخت هم اين کار رو ميکني؟ تيک، تف، هي، مي
You must be a great fuckin' shag.
تو بايد رقاص خوبي باشي
You takin' the piss?!
کسشعر داري ميي!؟
You're fuckin' givin' it away, aren't yer?
تو به وضوح داري اين رو نشون ميدي
Fuckin' come on, cunt! Kick your fucking' head open!!
خفه شو اقال! مغزت رو داغون ميکنم
What's it like being you?
بعد مثل تو ميشه؟
Bit hectic?
يج؟
Fuck off, poof!
خفه شو، فففف
Do you believe in self-fulfillin' prophecies?
تو به يشويي هاي خود محرک اعتقاد داري؟
You know, like, Nostradamus?
ميدوني، مثلا، نوستراداموس
'E was like this sixteenth-century astrologer.
اون منجم صده ي شانزدهم بود
An''e wrote in one of 'is quatrains that this goon called Hister would invade Poland.
تو يکي از رباعي هاش نوشته بود که يک جاني به اسم هيستر به لهستان حمله ميکنه
So Hitler reads it, and thinks 'Hister: Hitler. Must mean me',
بعد هيتلر اون رو ميخونه و ميه هيستر:هيتلر احتمالا منظورش من بودم
and invades Poland.
و به لهستان حمله ميکنه
So when the guy prophesied that the world would end in 1999, which 'e did,
س وقتي طرف يشويي ميکنه که دنيا تا سال 1999 به آخر خواهد رسيد، که اين کارم کرده
does that therefore mean that we're fulfilling the prophecy
اين نتيجه رو ميتونيم بيريم که ما داريم يشويي رو
by precipitatin' the Apocalypse?
با سرعت بخشيدن به روز قيامت تکميل ميکنيم
Are you with me?
وشت با منه؟
Do you think the world will end in 1999?
فکر ميکني سال 1999 دنيا به آخر ميرسه؟
Listen, mate, what d'you think to this?
وش کن رفيق، نظرت راجع به اين يه؟
Why don't you 'ave a little wander round and go look for the wee lassie, an' I'll wait 'ere?
را نميري يک رخ بزني و دنبال دخترکت بردي و من اينجا منتظر بمونم؟
And if she turns up, I'll keep 'er 'ere till you get back? 'Ow does that grab you?
و اه يداش شده، نهش ميدارم اينجا تا تو برردي
Are you're gonna be here, aye?
تو اينجا ميموني، آره؟
Right. If she gets back, right, tell her to fuckin' wait here till I get back.
آره. اه برشت، بهش بو از اينجا جم نخوره تا من برردم
If she wanders off, knock her oot. And slap her gob for me, right?
اه خواست بره ناکارش کن، از طرف من بزن تو دهنش، باشه؟
- Yeah, I'll tie her up. - Aye.
باشه، ميبندمش خوبه
- You're gonna be here, aye? - Yeah.
تو اينجا ميموني، نه؟ آره
Oh, listen, what's her name again?
ببين يه بار ديه اسمش رو ميي؟
Maggie.
مي
- Oh, yeah. - Will back in a minute, right?
آهان، خوبه زود بر ميردم، باشه؟
Excuse me, love.
ببخشيد عزيزم
Hallo?!
سلام
Are you Maggie ?
تو مي هستي؟
Piss off!
مشو
- Oh, you're Maggie ? - Wha' ?
هان؟
- Is your name Maggie ? - How d'ye ken that?
اسمت ميه؟ از کجا ميدوني؟
It's just a hunch. Are you looking for the petulant dwarf?
حدس زدم. دنبال اون کوتوله ي بداخلاق ميردي؟
Sprechen Sie Deutsch ?
Sprechen Sie Deutsch ?
Archie !
آري
Yeah, that's the fella. I was told to wait 'ere for you.
آره خودشه به من فته که اينجا منتظر تو بمونم
You, Maggie, 'e's, Archie, I'm nobody - 'e's gone off looking for you, love.
تو مي هستي، اون آري، من هم که هيي اون رفته دنبال تو عزيزم
What, you've seen 'um?
ي، تو اون رو ديدي؟
Look, would you come and sit over 'ere, now?
ببين ميشه بياي و اينجا بشيني؟
Fuck off, you dirty cunt!
اله ي کثيفت رو ببند
Yeah, well, I know I've not 'ad bath for a good few seasons,
آره، خب، من ند فصلي ميشه که حموم نرفتم
but there's no need to 'urt my feelin's.
ولي دليلي نداره که به احساساتم آسيب بزني
'E'll be back in a minute!
اون تا يک دقيقه ديه بر ميرده
What, he's been here?
ي؟ اون اينجا بوده؟
He's been here. He's been there. He's been all over the fuckin' shop.
اون اينجا بوده، اونجا بوده تمام مدت کنار اون مغازه ي لعنتي بوده
And did 'e 'ave the chips wi' 'um?
ول هم همراهش بود؟
He had a huge one on 'is shoulder.
يک يز بزر رو دوشش بود
Fuckin' wee radge!
کوتوله ي احمق
Oh, come now, there's no need to knock the young lad,
اوه، بي خيال، لازم نيست راجع به سرک اينطوري حرف بزني
He's a wonderful exponent of the old Socratic debate.
اون يک شارح فوق العاده ي مناظره هاي سقراطه
Listen love, I've got this great idea.
وش کن عزيزم، من يک ايده ي خوب دارم
Why don't you 'ave a little wander round, see if you can find the wee lad, an' I wait 'ere.
را نميري يک رخي بزني و ببيني ميتوني سرک رو يدا کني و من اينجا منتظر بمونم؟
An' if 'e turns up, I'll keep 'im 'ere until you get back
و اه يداش شد من نهش ميدارم تا تو برردي
I'm fuckin' starvin'.
من خيلي رسنمه
D'you wanna get somethin' to eat?
ميخواي يزي بيري بخوري؟
He's got all money, hasn't 'e?
تمام ول ها دست اونه، نه؟
- Who? Laughing Boy? - Aye.
کي؟ اون سرک مزحک؟ آره
Well, I've got a few bob on me.
خب، من ند شيلين با خودم دارم
And what if he comes back when noone's here?
و ي ميشه اه اون بررده، وقتي کسي اينجا نيست؟
We'll leave 'em a note
ما براش يادداشت ميذاريم
He'll no be able to read it.
اون خوندن بلد نيست
Well, we'll get 'im on his bleeper - come on
خب براش يجر ميفرستيم، بيا
Can you feel all those vibrations?
ميتوني اين لرزش ها رو حس کني؟
Wha'?
ي؟
Just stand still a minute, love. Try and feel it through your feet.
فقط يک دقيقه ثابت وايسا تا قشن با اهات حسشون کني
D'you not get all those tremblin's and rumblin's comin' up through your bones?
حس نميکني که تمام لرزش ها و صدا ها از استخوان هات بالا ميان؟
Not really, no.
نه واقعا، نه
D'you not get like a sense of, like, a whole other world underneath all this?
يک حسي داري که مثل يک دنياي ديه اي اين زيره؟
You know like the guts of London?
ميدوني، مثل دل و روده ي لندن؟
What with all the tube trains and everything, the city's viscera and the subterranean fuckin'
با همه ي قطارها و خلاصه همه ي دل و روده ي شهر و
fistulas and conduits and colons and bunkers
راه باريکه ها و کانال ها و کولون ها و سنرها
and dungeons and tombs an' all that?
و سياهال ها و قبر ها و همه ي اين يزاي زير زميني؟
What about Hell? And the sewers, like?
جهنم ي؟ يا مجرا هاي فاضلاب؟
- You know that wherever you are in London, you're only 30 feet away from a rat? - Aye?
ميدوني تو هر جاي لندن که باشي يک موش صحرايي در فاصله ي 30 فوتي تو قرار داره؟ جدا؟
- Does that freak you out? - Nah.
هيجان زده شدي؟ نه
- D'you believe in hell? - Aye.
تو به جهنم اعتقاد داري؟ آره
- So, d'you believe in the devil?
س به شيطان هم اعتقاد داري؟
What d'you think 'e looks like?
فکر ميکني ه شکلي باشه؟
Looks like that, doesn' 'e?
شبيه اينه، نه؟
What, a little nudist homunculus with a pink quiff?
ي؟ يک آدمک برهنه را با موهاي سيخ صورتي؟
No, 'e looks like a snake
نه، اون شبيه ماره
Let's 'ave a look at that
بذار يک ناهي بهش بندازم
It's Archie, isn't it?
اين آريه، درست نميم؟
It's my good-luck charm
اين بخت و اقبال منه
'As he brought you much?
زياد برات شانس آورده؟
Has it fuck.
اييده
- Are you superstituous? - No
تو خرافاتي اي؟ نه
What d'you wear a good-luck charm for, then?
س برا ي بخت و اقبال رو ردنت ميندازي؟
Are we gonna get something to eat or what?
داريم ميريم يزي بخوريم؟
Have you ever seen a dead body?
تا حالا جنازه ديدي؟
Only me own.
فقط خودم رو
Where was you thinkin' to sleepin' tonight?
امشب برا خوابيدن به فکر کجايي؟
Dunno.
نميدونم
Where did you kip down last night?
ديشب کجا خوابيدي؟
In the park.
تو ارک
- Was that not cold? - Aye.
سرد نبود؟ را
Where are you thinkin' of sleepin', like?
تو کجا ميخوابي؟
Wherever I drop.
هرجا که بيافتم
'Ow old are you, love?
ند سالته، عزيزم؟
Twenty-three
بيست و سه
- Do your mam and dad know you're down 'ere? - No.
مامان و بابات ميدونن که تو اينجايي؟ نه
- Will they not be worried about you? - No
نرانت نميشن؟
How old are you, like?
تو ند سالته؟
'Ow old d'you think I am?
تو فکر ميکني ند سالم باشه؟
About forty.
حدود هل
I'm twenty-seven.
بيست و هفت سالمه
Oh, get to fuck!
برو مشو
Where the fuck 'a you been?
کدوم وري بودي؟
I've been waitin' on yer!
تو کدوم وري بودي؟ من اينجا منتظر تو بودم
- Fuck off! - Cunt!
مشو جنده
Why the fuck you've been doin', eh?
را اين کار رو کردي؟
You've got all the money.
کل ول ها دست تو بود
I've been fuckin'g lookin' all over for yer.
من تمام اين مدت داشتم دنبال تو ميشتم
Aye, well, I was wi' him!
آره، خب، من با اون بودم
- Were you fuck! - I fuckin' was!
با اون بودي؟ آره بودم
- I was fuckin' wi' him!
من با اون بودم
Daft cunt!
جنده ي ابله
- Fuckin' ask him! - Fuck off!
ازش برس خفه شو
- Fuckin' daft bitch! - Where's my chips?
جنده ي آشغال عوضي ول من کجاست؟
That was fuckin' years ago.
اون مال سالها يش بود
Aye, well, I was starvin' wasn't I?
آره، خب، من رسنه ام بود
- I'll fuckin' gi' yer fuckin' chips! - Fuck off!
الان ولت رو بهت ميدم برو مشو
- Fuckin' leave us alone!
تنهامون بذار
- Kick your fuckin' cunt
مي کُنمت
Did he 'urt you?
اون تو رو ميزد؟
What d'you mean?
منظورت يه؟
You know, when you were fuckin'?
خودت ميدوني، وقتي داشتين همدير رو ميکردين
Why? Did he 'urt you?
طور؟ تو رو زد؟
D'you thing you were made for each other?
فکر ميکني شماها براي همديه ساخته شدين؟
Well, we went out for a year.
خب، ما يک ساله که از هم جدا شديم
A year?! Fuckin''ell - gimme a year!
يک ساله؟ بي خيال
D'you ever feel like topping yourself?
D'you ever feel like topping yourself?
Oh, God! I wish I was at 'ome
اوه، خداي من! کاش الان خونه بودم
Glad I'm not.
من خوشحالم که نيستم
Yeah, well, I don't mean with me mum and dad. I just mean in Manchester.
آره، خب، منظورم يش مامان و بابام نيست منظورم منستره
Oh, you reckon it's different there, do you?
اوه، تو فکر ميکني اونجا فرق داره؟
- Yeah - people talk to you. - Well, I'm talkin' to you.
آره، مردم باهات حرف ميزنن خب، منم دارم باهات حرف ميزنم
Yeah, but you talk a pile of shit.
آره منتها تو يه مشت مزخرف تحويل من ميدي
Don't matter where are you, anyway.
به هر حال، مهم نيست که کجا باشي
You might as well be in Zimbabwe with Sandra.
ممکن بود که تو الان توي زيمباوه کنار ساندرا باشي
Are you gonna do any washin' up before she gets back?
تو قبل از اين که اون بررده نظافت ميکني؟
Yeah, course I am. When is she gettin' back?
البته که آره کي بر ميرده؟
Sunday.
شنبه
Well, that's four fuckin' days away, innit?
خب، هار روز کوفتي مونده، مه نه؟
"Thou shalt not consent unto Him, nor harken unto Him."
تو نبايد با او موافقت کني نه به او وش فرا دهي
"Neither shall thine eye pity Him, neither shalt thou spare",
نه شمانت براي او احساس ترحم کنند نه او را ببخشي
"neither shalt thou conceal 'Im. But thou shalt surely kill 'Im. Thy ha..."
نه او را نهان کني ولي تو قطعا بايد او را به قتل برساني. تو
Lost me place now.
يادم رفت کجا بودم
"And thou shalt stone 'Im with stones, that He die
و تو نبايد او را با سني سنسار کني که بميرد
because He hath sought to thrust thee away from the Lord thy God. And -"
زيرا که او به دنبال اين بوده که تو را از روردارت دور کند. و
Oh, fuckin' 'ell! Why 'ast though forsaken me? Bastard!"
اوه لعنتي! س تو را من رو ترکم کردي؟ حرومزاده
Is that it now, then? Are you through with the regulation pacin'?
خب، همين؟ بعدش؟ داري رژه ي وظيفه ات رو ميري؟
You're all set to deploy the fatuous sarcasm?
شما رو ذاشتن اينجا که اين مسخره بازي هاي احمقانه ي رو در بيارين؟
Well, I've beaten you to it.
منم بهت کمک ميکنم
Would you like a mint?
نعنا ميخواي؟
Oh, what's this, new policy? Ply the culprit with menthol?
اوه، اين يه؟ سياست جديده؟ متهم رو با قرص نعنا مشغول ميکنين؟
Extra strong.
خيلي قويه
I get four packets of these a night
يک شب 4 تا بسته از اينا رفتم
You want be careful, don't yer? I don't want your poxy mint.
ميخواي با احتياط عمل کني، نه؟ من اين نعناي آشغالت رو نميخوام
Oh? Waste not, want not.
اوه، اه نميخواي حرومش نکن
And other cliches.
و کليشه اي دير
Ah - but a cliche is full of truth, otherwise it wouldn't be a cliche.
ولي کليشه سرشار از حقيقته، در غير اين صورت که کليشه نميشد
Which is in itself a cliche.
اين هم خودش کليشه است
Tell me, have you
بو ببينم
read the book of Hosea?
تو کتاب هوشع رو خوندي؟
What now?
که ي؟
"For they are the children of whores".
ون آنها فرزندان روسيانند
There's no need to get personal, mate.
لازم نيست خيلي صميمي بشي رفيق
Look, will you stop fucking about?
ببين، ميشه دست از اين کارها بر داري؟
If you're gonna stick the boot in, will you get on with it?
فکر ميکني اه سيريش بشي، به خواستت ميرسي؟
Have you got nowhere to go, then?
س جايي رو نداري که بري؟
Yeah, I've got an infinite number of fuckin' places to go.
را، بينهايت جا هست که من بتونم برم
The problem is, where you stay.
مهم اينه که کجا بموني
Are you with me?
حواست با منه؟
Indeed. Yes.
آره. البته
So listen, is there much security
س وش کن. امنيت زيادي
in this job?
توي اين کاره؟
Too much.
خيلي زياد
And what is it what goes on in this particular postmodernist gas chamber?
و اين ي هست؟ ي توي اين اتاق از ست مدرن ويژه وجود داره؟
Nothing. It's empty.
هيي. خاليه
So what is it that you're guardin'?
س تو از ي حفاظت ميکني؟
Space.
فضا
You're guarding space?
تو محافظ فضايي؟
That's stupid, innit? Because someone could break in there, right, and steal all the fuckin' space,
مسخره است، نه؟ ون يکي ميتونه ناهان وارد بشه و تمام اون فضاي لعنتي رو بدزده
and you wouldn't know it 'ad gone, would you?
و تو نميفهمي که نين اتفاقي افتاده، ميفهمي؟
Good point.
نکته ي خوبيه
Night-night.
شب بخير
Yeah, all right, pal. I appreciate you've got a job to do, an' it's "Move on! Move on! Move on!"
باشه رفيق، من ميفهمم که تو کاري براي انجام دادن داري و اون اينه "برو، برو، برو
But it's fuckin' freezin' out there, an' I was a Caesarian.
But it's fuckin' freezin' out there, an' I was a Caesarian.
Come on, quick!
سريع بيا تو
- What? - Come in.
ي؟ بيا تو
Are you serious?
جدي ميي؟
Through that door... smartish.
از اون در، مراقب باش
It's a funny smell in 'ere.
بوي عجيبي مياد
Come on.
بيا
A bit of waste of space, all this, in't it?
يکم فضاي اضافه، فقط همين، غير از اينه؟
You could sleep a thousand flea-bitten tramps in 'ere.
تو ميتوني هزار تا خانه بدوش کک زيده رو اينجا بخوابوني
And what's all that?
اينا يه؟
You know, they say it's a fuckin' jungle out there? 'Ave you seen it in 'ere?
ميدوني، بيرون مين که اين يک جنله؟ تو اينا رو اينجا ديدي؟
I mean, where's the bloody monkeys?
منظورم اينه که، ميمون هاي لعنتي کجان؟
Look, Dad, will you just back off?! What is it you're after?
ببين، آقاجان، ميشه بري عقب؟ دنبال ي هستي؟
- You must be invisible. - What?
تو بايد نامعلوم باشي ي؟
I must be seen.
من بايد ديده شم
Follow me.
دنبال من بيا
Sit here.
بشين اينجا
Am I allowed to smoke in here?
ميتونم اينجا سيار بکشم؟
No. You'll set off the alarm.
نه، آژير رو به صدا در مياري
Now, I'm not gonna look at you.
حالا، من به تو ناه نميکنم
It mustn't look like I'm talking to anybody.
نبايد به نظر بياد که من دارم با کسي صحبت ميکنم
If you're seen in here, I'm out of a job.
اه تو اينجا ديده بشي، من اخراجم
See what I mean?
ميفهمي ي ميم؟
Well, if they see you talking to yourself like that, you'll be out of a job anyway.
خب، اه اونها تو رو ببينن که به اين حالت داري با خودت حرف ميزني، باز هم اخراج ميشي
They'll come after you with a big butterfly net.
اونا با يک تور بزر شکار روانه ميان سراغت
Oh, yes.. I'll stand like this, then.
اوه، بله...س من اينطوري مي ايستم
Well, that's better, isn't it?
خب، اين بهتره، نه؟
What?
ي؟
In out of the cold?
داخل، به دور از سرما؟
Yeah. Yeah - thanks very much.
بله، بله، خيلي ممنونم
It's funny bein' inside, in't it?
مسخره است که داخل باشي، نه؟
'Cos when you are inside, you're still actually outside, aren't you?
ون وقتي که داخلي، در واقع هنوز بيروني، نه؟
And then you can say when you're outside, you're inside,
و بعد ميتوني بي که: وقتي که بيروني، داخلي
because you're always inside your head.
ون تو هميشه داخل مغزتي
D'you follow that?
حواست هست؟
Yes. Sometimes when I'm sitting here, I turn the lights off -
آره، بعضي وقت ها که اينجا نشستم راغ ها رو خاموش ميکنم
sit in the dark.
و توي تاريکي مينشينم
That always makes me feel like I'm sitting
و هميشه به من اين حس رو ميده که بيرون
outside.
نشستم
So what d'you do with you self here of a night-time?
خب، شبها اينجا ي کار ميکني؟
I read. And I think.
مطالعه ميکنم، و فکر ميکنم
What do you think about?
راجع به ي فکر ميکني؟
I think about my life.
راجع به زنديم
- And is that horrendous for you? - No! Certainly not!
و اين برات وحشتناکه؟ نه! واقعا نه
Is it horrendous for your wife?
براي زنت وحشتناکه؟
Are you married, mate?
تو ازدواج کردي، رفيق؟
Well, technically I'm married.
آره، از لحاظ قانوني ازدواج کردم
Although my wife is 5,919 miles away,
اره زنم 5,919 مايل دورتر از منه
and I haven't seen her for thirteen years.
و سيزده سال ميشه که نديدمش
It's all going very well then. Where is she?
بالاخره همه ي درست ميشه اون کجاست؟
She's in Bangkok.
تو بانکک
Saucy!
ه خوب
- They're not worth it, are they? - Whores and harlots.
اونا ارزشش رو ندارن، دارن؟ روسيان و فاحشان
When was the last time you 'ad a fuck?
آخرين باري که همدير رو کردين کي بود؟
Is that an embarassin' question for you?
براي تو، اين سوال خجالت آوريه؟
It is rather - yes.
نسبتا - آره
I'm sorry.
شرمنده
Step this way.
بيا اين طرف
I want to reveal to you the mysteries of my trade.
من ميخوام اسرار شغلم رو برات فاش کنم
What d'you think that is?
فکر ميکني اين يه؟
A Dadaist nun?
يک راهبه ي دادئيست؟
Wrong. This little lady is the representative of my employer.
اشتباه بود. اين خانم کوولو نماينده ي کارفرماي منه
How d'you do, love?
طوري، عزيزم؟
Watch.
ناه کن
Very Zen.
Very Zen
My existence at this moment on this spot is now trapped and recorded.
وجود من در اين نقطه اکنون ثبت شد
23 moments, 23 sites, every two hours.
هر دو ساعت در 23 لحظه و 23 مکان
That's my job.
شغل من اينه
Well, could they not train a tall chimpanzee to do that?
خب، اونا نميتونن يک شامانزه ي قد بلد رو براي اين کار تربيت کنن؟
Or, a small chimpanzee with a bigger gizmo?
يا يک قدر کوتاه با يک دستاه بزرتر؟
I suppose they could, yes.
فکر کنم بتونن، آره
What's your name, son?
اسمت يه سر؟
- Brian. - Hallo Brian - Johnny.
برايان سلام برايان - جاني
Well, Brian, congratulations, you've succeeded in convincin' me
خب، برايان، تبريک ميم. تو در متقاعد کردن من به اينکه
that you do 'ave the most tedious fuckin' job in England.
ملالت آورترين کار در انليس رو داري موفق شدي
Come on.
بيا
- Yes! It is a boring job! Bloody boring, actually. - All right! All right!
آره، اين يک کار خسته کننده است در حقيقت خيلي خست کننده باشه، باشه
But all you can see is the tip of the iceberg.
ولي تمام اون يزي که تو ميتوني ببيني قطره اي از يک درياست
The present. The tedious here and now.
زمان حال. الان ملالت آوره
What you're not capable of seeing is the rest of time - the rest of the iceberg.
يزي که تو قادر نيستي ببيني باقي زمانه باقي دريا
The past and the future.
ذشته و آينده
My future. Which is a very interesting place to be.
آينده ي من. جاي خيلي جالبي خواهد بود
And the good thing about this job is that it gives me time and space
و خوبي اين کار اينه که به من زمان و مکان ميده
to contemplate the future at my leisure.
تا در اوقات فراغتم به آينده ام بيانديشم
Whilst the city sleeps.
وقتي که شهر در خواب به سر ميبره
Free from cacophonous curiosity of the hoi polloi.
آزاد از کنجکاوي نا به هنجار توده ي مردم
So you see, it's not a boring job.
خب، س ميبيني که اين کار خسته کننده اي نيست
And I'm not boring, either.
و من هم خسته کننده نيستم
Am I allowed to smoke on the stairs?
ميتونم تو راه له سيار بکشم؟
No. There's alarms all over the building.
نه، آژير ها همه جاي ساختمون هستند
So you think you can make the present palatable by projectin' into the future?
س تو فکر ميکني که ميتوني حال رو مطبوع به ذائقه کني، ار که به آينده ن بندازي؟
You're living in the past, pal. It's the future that fucks you up, Brian.
تو در ذشته زندي ميکني رفيق اين آينده است که تو رو به ا ميده برايان
It's the maggot in the apple.
يک کرم در سيبه
See, you're all pissed off with the present, Bri, and there's nothing wrong with the present.
ببين، تو داري ند ميزني به زمان حال، برايان ولي زمان حال هي مشکلي نداره
The present's fine. The present's perfect.
حال خوبه. حال محشره
The present's peachy-fuckin'-creamy.
حال فوق العاده است
The only thing wrong with the present is the bastard doesn't exist,
تنها مشکلي که حال داره، اينه که لعنتي وجود نداره
Because the present is the future, and the future is the past.
براي اينکه حال، آينده است و آينده، ذشته است
And it's all the same fuckin' bag of bones anyway.
And it's all the same fuckin' bag of bones anyway
It's a constant process of comin' into bein' and passin' away, comin' into bein' and passin' away.
اين يک روال ثابته که زندي کني و بميري زندي کني و بميري
The future is now.
آينده الانه
But the present does exist. We're in it, now.
ولي حال وجود داره. ما الان درونشيم
You were just then when you said it, but you're not in it now, you're not in it now, you're not in it now. You're forever being kicked up
وقتي که اين رو فتي درونش بودي، ولي الان ديه نه الان ديه نيستي، الان ديه نيستي. و تو تا ابد
the arse by the future. Are you with me?
کونت اره ميشه، وشت با منه؟
That's what I mean. See, I'm in the present.
من هم همين رو ميم. ببين، من در زمان حال هستم
But I'm not in the present. I'm in the future.
ولي در زمان حال نيستم، در زمان آينده ام
Exactly.
دقيقا
Has nobody not told you, Brian,
برايان تا به حال کسي بهت نفته
that you've got this kind of gleeful preoccupation with the future?
که تو خيلي به آينده علاقه مندي؟
I wouldn't even mind, but you don't even 'ave a fuckin' future.
من اهميت نميدم، ولي تو حتي آينده هم نداري
I don't 'ave a future. Nobody 'as a future. The party's is over.
من آينده ندارم، هيکس آينده نداره، ضيافت تمام شد
Take a look around you, man. It's all breaking up.
يک ناه به دور و برت بنداز. همه يز داره از بين ميره
Are you not familiar with the book of Revelation of St John,
تو با کتاب وحي حضرت يوحنا آشنا نيستي؟
the final book of the Bible, prophesying the Apocalypse?
آخرين کتاب مقدس که قيامت رو يشويي ميکنه؟
Yes. As it happens, I'm familiar with all the books of the Bible.
را. اتفاقا، من با تمام کتب مقدس آشنا هستم
I'm very happy for you
خيلي برات خوشحالم
"He forced everyone to receive a mark on his right hand, or on his forehead,
اون همه رو مجبور ميکنه که رو دست راست يا شت سرشون رو، علامت ذاري کنن
so that no one shall be able to buy or sell,
س کسي نبايد توانايي اين رو داشته باشه که خريد و فروش کنه
unless he has the mark, which is the name of the beast.
مر اينکه علامت رو داشته باشه، که اسم اژدهاست
Or the number of his name; and the number of the beast is six-six-six.
يا شماره ي اسمش و شماره ي اژدها 666 هست
- Six-six-six. I know about it - Great!
آره، 666 من ازش مطلعم عاليه
I know about Nostradamus. Nostradamus talked about three brothers.
من نوستراداموس رو ميشناسم نوستراداموس راجع به سه برادر صحبت ميکنه
Now, did he mean the Kennedy brothers, or was he talking about three bits of the Soviet Union?
Now, did he mean the Kennedy brothers, or was he talking about three bits of the Soviet Union?
You see, you just can't tell.
ميبني، نميتوني جواب بدي
Fuck Nostradamus! I'm not talking about Nostradamus
ريدم به نوستراداموس. من راجع به نوستراداموس
or Mother Shipton or Russell Grant of Mystic fuckin' Meg -
و مادر شيتون و راسل رانت توي اون افسانه ي مزخرف حرف نميزنم
I'm talking about a Holy fuckin' Book!
من راجع به کتاب تخمي مقدس دارم صحبت ميکنم
What can such a specific prophecy mean?
نين يشويي ويژه اي ه معني ميتونه داشته باشه؟
What is the mark?
علامت، ي هست؟
Well the mark, Brian, is the bar code,
خب برايان، علامت بارکده
the ubiquitous barcode that you'll find on every bog-roll, on every packet of johnnies,
بارکدي که همه جا هست و تو حتي رو هر دستمال توالت و هر جعبه ي کاندوم
and every poxy pork pie.
و هر کلوه ي آشغالي ميتوني يداش کني
And every fuckin' bar code is divided into two parts by three markers.
و هر کدام از اين بارکدهاي کوفتي با سه علامت به دو بخش تبديل ميشه
And those three markers are always represented by the number six.
و اون سه علامت هميشه عدد 6 هستند
Six. Six. Six!
شش. شش. شش
Now what does it say? "No one shall be able to buy,
حالا معني اين يه؟ کسي بدون اون علامت
or sell, without that mark."
حق خريد و فروش رو نداره
And now, what they're plannin' to do in order to eradicate all credit-card fraud,
و حالا کاري که ميخوان بکنن اينه که کلاهبرداري هاي کارت هاي اعتباري رو ريشه کن بکنن
and in order to precipitate a totally cashless society,
و جامعه رو به سمت يک جامعه ي کاملا غير ولي سوق بدن
what they're plannin' to do, what they've already tested on the American troops,
کاري که ميخوان بکنن، کاري که در حال حاضر روي سربازهاي آمريکا تستش کردن
they're going to subcutaneously laser-tattoo that mark
اونا ميخوان علامت رو با ليزر زير وست
on to your right hand or on to your forehead.
دست راستت يا شت سرت خالکوبي کنن
They're going to replace plastic with flesh. Fact!
اونها لاستيک رو جايزين وشت ميکنن در حقيقت
In the same book of Revelation, when the seven seals are broken open on the Day of Judgement,
در همون کتابِ وحي، وقتي که مُهر هفتم در روز قضاوت ميشکنه و باز ميشه
and the seven angels blow the trumpets, when the third angel blows 'er bugle,
و هفت فرشته درون ترومت ميدمن وقتي که فرشته سوم شيورش رو ميزنه
"Wormwood will fall from the sky.
افسنطين از آسمان ميافته
Wormwood will poison a third part of all the waters,
افسنطين يک سوم آبها و يک سوم زمين ها
and a third part of all the land, and many, many, many, people will die."
رو مسموم ميکنه و تعداد خيلي، خيلي، خيلي زيادي از مردم کشته ميشن
Now, d'you know what the Russian translation for "wormwood" is?
و حالا ميدوني که ترجمه ي روسي افسنطين ي ميشه؟
- No - Chernobyl.
Chernobyl
Fact!
آره
On August the 18th, 1999,
در هجدهم آوست سال 1999
the planets of our solar system are going to line up into the shape of a cross.
سياره هاي منظومه ي شمسي ما به شکل يک صليب به خط ميشن
I don't believe in astrology.
من به اختربيني اعتقاد ندارم
I'm not talking about astrology. I'm talking about astromony.
من راجع به اختربيني زهرماري صحبت نميکنم من دارم راجع به اخترشناسي حرف ميزنم
They're going to line up in the fixed signs of Aquarius, Leo, Taurus,
اونها در جاهاي برج دلو، برج اسد، برج ثور
and Scorpio, which just happen to correspond with the four beasts of the Apocalypse,
برج عقرب رديف ميشن، که با هار اژدهاي روز قيامت مطابقت يدا کنند
as mentioned in the Book of Daniel.
همون طور که در کتاب دانيال ذکر شده
Another fuckin' fact! D'you want me to go on?
يک حقيقت تخمي ديه! ميخواي ادامه بدم؟
The end of the world is nigh, Bri. The game is up!
ايان دنيا نزديکه برايان. بازي تمومه
I don't believe that.
من باور نميکنم
Life can't just come to a stop.
نميشه که زندي تموم بشه
All right, I'm not sayin' that life will end, or the world will end,
باشه، من نميم که زندي تموم ميشه يا دنيا به ايان ميرسه
or the universe will cease to exist.
يا تمام عالم از بين ميره
But Man will cease to exist.
ولي انسان از بين ميره
Just like the dinosaurs passed into extinction, the same thing'll happen to us.
مثل دايناسور ها که انقراض يدا کردن همون اتفاق براي ما هم مي افته
We're not fuckin' important. We're just a crap idea!
ما هي اهميتي نداريم ما فقط يک ايده ي مزخرفيم
I'm not gonna cease to exist.
من از بين نخواهم رفت
I'm gonna be here in the future.
من در آينده اينجا خواهم بود
What is this fuckin' fixation with the future?!
اين تعلق خاطر لعنتيت به آينده يه؟
Listen pal, I've got chronic systolic palpitations
وش کن رفيق، من ناراحتي مزمن قلبي و
and acute fuckin' neuralgia!
درد اعصاب خيلي شديد دارم
What about these toilets - can I smoke in 'ere?
تو اين دستشويي لعنتي که ميتونم سيار روشن کنم؟
No, you fuckin' can't!
نه خير، حق نداري
Let me ask you a question.
بذار يک سوال ازت برسم
Have you ever had the sense that you've lived in a time different from this one?
تا حالا اين حس رو داشتي که در يک زماني به جز الان زندي کردي؟
- What you mean like in a past life? - Could be, yeah.
منظورت زندي ذشته است؟ ميتونه باشه
Yeah, well, in my past life I was dead.
آره، تو زندي ذشته ام مرده بودم
Ah, well, you see - I wasn't.
خب، ميبني - من نمرده بودم
I know I was here in the past, before I was born.
من ميدونم که در ذشته اينجا بودم، قبل از اينکه متولد بشم
So I know I'm gonna be here in the future after I've died.
س من ميدونم که بعد از مردنم هم اينجا خواهم بود
I see.
ميفهمم
And in this alternative existence,
و در اين زندي ديرت هم
did you still 'ave the same noxious body odour?
اين بوي ند عرقت رو همراهت خواهي داشت؟
There's no need to be personal. It's what I believe.
لازم نيست وارد مسائل شخصي بشي اين يزيه که من بهش اعتقاد دارم
Shall I tell you what I believe?
من هم بايد بم که به ي اعتقاد دارم؟
You don't believe anything.
تو به هي يز اعتقاد نداري
Oh, I do, Brian.
را، دارم برايان
Yeah? What do you believe?
خب؟ به ي اعتقاد داري؟
Do you think the amoeba ever dreamed that it would evolve into the frog?
تو فکر ميکني تک سلولي، هي وقت خواب اين رو که به وزغ تبديل بشه ميديده؟
Of course it didn't.
البته که نميديده
And when that first frog shimmied out of the water and employed it's vocal chords
وقتي اولين وزغ از آب ريد بيرون و داشت ابوعطا ميخوند
in order to attract a mate or to retard a predator,
که جفتش رو جذب کنه يا خودش رو از نال شکاري رهايي بده
do you think that that frog ever imagined that that incipient croak would evolve into
تو فکر ميکني که اون وزغ هي وقت تصور ميکرد که اون صداي اوليه اش تکامل يدا کنه به
all the languages of the world,
تمام زبان هاي دنيا
into all the literature of the world?
تمام ادبيات دنيا؟
'Course it fuckin' didn't.
البته که عمرا نميکرد
And just as that froggy could never have possibly conceived of - of Shakespeare,
و درست همونطور که اون وزغ هي وقت نميتونست به شکسير فکر کنه
we can never possibly imagine our destiny.
ما هم ممکن نيست که بتونيم سرنوشتمون رو تصور کنيم
I know what my destiny is.
من ميدونم سرنوشتم يه
Yeah but what you're experiencing, as far as I can gather what with all these manifestations of
آره، ولي اون يزي که تو ميتوني تجربه کني تا جايي که من ميفهمم با تمام اين اظهارات
regression and precognition
واس روي و از يش آاهي
and transmigratory astral fuckin' chatterin's,
و تناسخي و تصادمي
is just the equivalent of that first primeval grunt.
فقط برابر با اولين صداي وزغه است
Because evolution isn't over.
ون تکامل تمام نشده
Man isn't the fuckin' be-all and fuckin' end-all.
انسان نه تمام وجوده نه ايان اون
Look. If you take the whole of time represented by one year,
ببين. اه تو تمام زمان رو يک سال در نظر بيري
we're only in the first few moments of the 1st of January.
ما الان فقط در اولين لحظات اول ژانويه هستيم
There's a long way to go.
راه زيادي مونده براي رفتن
Only now we're not going to sprout extra limbs and wings and fins
ما الان نميتونيم جوارح جديد و ر و بال داشته باشيم
because evolution itself is evolving.
براي اينکه تکامل خودش هم تکامل يدا ميکنه
And whereas you, through some process of extra-sensory recall,
اره تو از طريق يک سري يادآوري هاي فراحسي
might imagine that you were some -
ممکنه تصور کني که يک
I dunno, some 17th century little Dutch girl livin' in a windmill in Old Amsterdam,
نميدونم، يک دختر کوولوي هلندي قرن هفدهمي که در آمستردام زندي ميکرده بودي
one day you'll realize that you've had not just one or two
روزي خواهي فهميد که تو تنها
past or future existences,
يک زندي قبل و بعد نداشتي
but that you were, and are, everybody and everything that 'as ever been,
بلکه تو بودي، تو هستي همه کس و همه يز هميشه بوده اند
or will ever be.
و تا ابد خواهند بود
Hang on a minute. You've just contradicted yourself.
يک دقيقه صبر کن. تو الان خودت رو نقض کردي
Oh, and 'ow'd you make that out?
اوه، طور به اين نتيجه رسيدي؟
Downstairs you were predicting the end of the world.
زير له ها تو داشتي ايان جهان رو يشبيني ميکردي
Now you're talking about the future.
الان داري راجع به آينده صحبت ميکني
How do you explain that, eh?
جطوري اين رو توضيح ميدي؟
Easy.
به سادي
When it comes, the Apocalypse itself
وقتي روز قيامت برسه، خودش
will be part of the process of that leap of evolution.
قسمتي از تکامل خواهد بود
Yeah, well, whatever happens, mankind will not cease to exist.
آره، باشه، هر اتفاقي که بيافته حيات بشر متوقف نميشه
He must. By the very definition of Apocalypse, Mankind must cease to exist,
بايد بشه. بر اساس خيلي از مشخصات روز قيامت بايد بشه
at least in a material form.
حداقل در ابعاد مادي
What d'you mean, in a material form?
منظورت يه، از درابعاد مادي؟
Well, 'e'll evolve.
خب، ما تکامل يدا ميکنيم
What into?
به ي؟
Into something that transcends matter.
به يزي که از ماده فراتر بره
Into a species of pure thought. Are you with me?
به يک نوع فکر محض. حواست با منه؟
Yeah. Like a ghost.
آره. مثل يک روح
No, not like a fuckin' ghost, you big girl's blouse!
نه يک روح، جناب هالو
Into something that's, like, well beyond our comprehension.
به يزي که مثلا، وراي درک ما باشه
Into a universal consciousness,
به يک آاهي کيهاني
Into God. Who is.
به خدا. که وجود داره
By the same principle that time is.
بر همون مبنا که اين زمان، وجود داره
You don't believe in God.
تو به خدا اعتقاد نداري
'Course I believe in God.
البته که اعتقاد دارم
You see... The thing is, Brian
ميبيني، برايان، مساله اينه که
that God is a hateful God.
اون خدا، يک خداي نفرت انيزه
Must be, because if God is good,
بايد هم باشه، براي اينکه اه خدا خوبه
then why is there evil in the world?
س را شيطان توي دنيا وجود داره؟
Why is there pain and hate and greed and war?
براي ي اينجا رنج و کينه و طمع و دشمني وجود داره؟
It doesn't make sense.
اين بي معنيه
But if God is a nasty bastard, then you can say, why is there good in the world?
ولي اه خدا يک کثافت حرومزاده باشه اونوقت ميتوني بي، را خوبي توي جهان وجود داره؟
Why is there love and hope and joy?
را عشق، اميد و لذت وجود داره؟
Well, let's face it, good exists
خب، بيا فکر کنيم، خير وجود داره
in order to be fucked up by evil.
که به وسيله ي شر از بين بره
The very existence of good enables evil to flourish.
حضور مکرر نيکي باعث ميشه که شر خودش رو نشون بده
Therefore, God is bad.
بنابراين خدا بده
And it doesn't matter how many past or future existences you have,
و مهم نيست ند تا زندي در ذشته و آينده داشته باشي
because they're all going to be riddled with grief and anguish
ون که همشون مملو از غم و اندوه و
and sickness and death.
مريضي و مر ميشن
You see Brian, God doesn't love you.
ببين برايان، خدا تو رو دوست نداره
God despises you.
خدا از تو متنفره
So there's no hope.
س اميدي نيست
Mankind is just a component of the device
بشر فقط مولفه ي يک وسيله هستش که
by which the devil creates itself.
شيطان به وسيله ي اون خودش رو توليد ميکنه
You with me?
حواست به منه؟
You see, what I'm saying, basically, is you can't make an omelette without crackin' a few eggs,
ميبيني، يزي که من دارم ميم در واقع اينه که تو نميتوني بدون اينکه ند تا تخم مرغ بشکني، املت درست کني
and humanity is just a cracked egg. And the omelette
و انسان فقط يک تخم مرغ شکسته شده است و املت
stinks.
بوي ند ميده
Yeah.
آره
Oh. And what's through the round window?
اوه، تو اون نجره ي رد ه خبره؟
'Oo's that?
اون کيه؟
Good question.
سوال خوبيه
'Ave you seen 'er before?
قبلا هم ديده بوديش؟
Oh yeah. She's there every night.
آره. هر شب اونجاست
Good-looking young girl, in't she?
يک دختر زيباي جوان، نه؟
She's all right.
اون خيلي خوبه
Does she ever 'as fellers up there?
تا حالا مردي، بالا باهاش بوده؟
No.
نه
'Ave you ever seen 'er, like, you know, totally naked?
تا حالا اون رو کاملا برهنه ديدي؟
Once.
يک دفعه
What's she up to, eh?
ميخواد ي کار کنه، ها؟
I mean, what's her game, taunting people in the middle of the night, eh?
منظورم اينه که، تفريحش اينه نصف شب مردم رو تحريک کنه؟
She probably gets a kick out of it. Like you get a kick out o' watching 'er.
اون احتمالا با اين کار سررم ميشه همونطور که تو سررم ناه کردنش شدي
I'm doing no such thing.
نه، من نشدم
Well, I am.
خب، من شدم
'Ave your got a 'ard-on?
تو شق کردي؟
No, I haven't, as a matter of fact.
نه، واقعا
You wouldn't tell me if you had, would you?
اه کرده بودي به من نميفتي، ميفتي؟
No, I don't think I would.
نه. فکر نميکنم
- Did you make these youself? - I did, yeah.
تو خودت اينا رو درست کردي؟ آره
I thought so.
فکرش رو ميکردم
Well, listen, I might be back in a couple of minutes.
خب، وش کن، من ممکنه ند دقيقه ي ديه بر ردم
Be good. If you can't be good, be careful!
سر خوبي باش. اه نميتوني، مراقب باش
And other cliches.
و يک کليشه ي ديه
Tatty-bye, Bri.
بدرود، برايان
Charles !
ارلس
What?!
ي؟
Mais il est ou alors? Ecoute, je ne sais pas qui vous etes.
Mais il est ou alors? Ecoute, je ne sais pas qui vous etes.
What's the fuck's going on? Where the bloody hell's Dorfman,
معلوم هست ه خبره؟ دورفمن لعنتي کجاست؟
the bastard costs me 30 grands already!
حرومزاده تا الان 30 راند هزينه رو دست من انداخته
Quoi?!
Quoi?!
Qu'est-ce qui se passe?
Qu'est-ce qui se passe?
Fuck !
ه
Sorry about that.
عذر ميخوام
Oh, I'm sorry, love. That's not you on the top floor, is it?
ببخشيد عزيزم. اين تو نبودي که اون بالا
- Dancin'? - Yeah. Why?
ميرقصيدي؟ آره، طور؟
Oh, right. You're a lovely mover.
خب، تو خيلي قشن تکون ميخوردي
I'm sorry pet. I'm freaking you out.
متاسفم عزيزم. ترسوندمت
Where's Bhapu?
باو کجاست؟
Bhapu?
باو؟
It's cold.
سرده
Listen, I'd better explain myself - you see me brother's working
وش کن، بهتره خودم توضيح بدم. ميبيني برادر من به عنوان مامور حفاظتي
as an insecurity guard in that fuckin' monstrosity round the back,
تو اون ساختمون غول آسا اون شت کار ميکنه
and we can see straight into your room.
و ما مستقيم ميتونيم اطاقت رو ببينيم
It's very nice.
خيلي خوبه
Anyway, 'e's got 'is boss comin' round. So 'e's told me to schlep round the streets
به هر حال، رئيسش داره مياد و به من فت دور خيابون ها ول برخم
for a couple of hours, and I said
براي ند ساعت و من فتم
I'd come and say 'ello to Isadora Duncan. Keep you company.
که ميرم که يه سلامي به ايزابلا دونکان عرض کنم همراهيت کنم
I know it's a big cheeky but I'm a cheeky young monkey!
ميدونم که خيلي جسارته، ولي من هم يک ميمون جوان جسورم
D'you wanna come in?
ميخواي بياي تو؟
Is that all right?
مشکلي نداره؟
How long you been growing that?
قدر اينا رو بلند کردي؟
About two inches.
حدود دو اين
It's nice.
خوشله
You've 'ad a few, an't you, love?
تو هم يکم داري، مه نه عزيزم؟
Do you wanna come in?
ميخواي بياي تو؟
Thought you'd never ask.
فکر نميکردم برسي
Am I allowed to smoke in 'ere?
ميتونم سيار روشن کنم؟
Thank Christ for that!
خدا رو شکر
D'you wanna a drink?
نوشيدني ميل داري؟
I think I better 'ad, don't you? Got a bit of fuckin' catchin' up to do, an't I?
فکر کنم بهتره بخورم، بايد تحرک زيادي داشته باشم، نه؟
Here's to the monarchy!
به سلامتي سلطنت
- What's funny? - I'm not laughing.
يش خنده داره؟ من نمي خندم
So, do you live 'ere on yer own, yeah?
تو تنها زندي ميکني، آره؟
Is this what you're reading? "Jane Austen" by Emma.
اين رو ميخوني؟ جين آستين اثر اما
It's my favorite book.
کتاب مورد علاقمه
Is it really?
جدا؟
I don't read much, meself.
من به شخصه خيلي مطالعات ندارم
You're from Ireland?
تو ايرلندي هستي؟
No.
نه
Why?
طور؟
What's that, a damp patch?
اون يه، رطوبت ديوار؟
Oh, I never noticed that before.
اوه، من تا حالا اين رو نديده بودم
'Ow's it goin' inside there?
اين تو ي ميذره؟
Baby.
عزيزم
'Ow old are you, love?
ند سالته عزيزم؟
It's funny, 'cos from over there you look a lot younger.
جالبه، ون از اون بيرون جوون تر به نظر مياي
I think me big brother's quite taken with you.
من فکر کنم برادر بزرم باهات جور در بياد
'E's up there every night, 'avin' a bit of a wank about yer.
اون هر شب اونجاست. با تو جلق ميزنه
Are you with me?
وشت با منه؟
What's the matter?
موضوع يه؟
Don't do that
اين کار رو نکن؟
What, that?
ي، اين؟
Or that?
يا اين؟
Don't you like that?
اين رو دوست نداري؟
You don't 'ave to 'urt me
حق نداري به من آسيب برسوني
I'm sorry
عذر ميخوام
Bite me.
ازم بير
Fuckin' bite me!
ازم بير لعنتي
Come on!
زود باش
'Oo's this?
اين کيه؟
I can't, love.
نميتونم عزيزم
You look like me mother.
تو جاي مادرم رو داري
D'you think you can recapture your youth by fuckin' it?
فکر ميکني که ميتوني جوونيت رو با اييدن به دست بياري؟
You don't want to fuck me - you'll catch something cruel.
تو نميخواي منو بايي، تو دنبال وحشي بازي ميردي
Bonjour
سلام
What's goin' on? What're you doin' 'ere?
ي شده؟ تو اين جا ي کار ميکني؟
Well, you see. I was over 'ere, like this,
خب، ميبيني. من روي اين بودم، اينطوري
but that didn't work for me, so I thought
بعد جواب نداد و فکر کردم
I'd try over here, but I don't think there's much future in this one either.
بيام رو اين يکي بايستم، ولي فکر نمي کنم اين رو هم خيلي بتونم دوام بيارم
Fuckin' 'ell! Have you got any suggestions?
به درک يشنهادي داري؟
So what do you do now?
خب الان يکار ميکني؟
I'm gonna get some breakfast
ميرم صبحونه بخورم
I could do somethin' to eat Can I come with yer?
خب، من هم ميتونم يک يزي براي خوردن بيونم ميتونم باهات بيام؟
Well, have you got any money?
خب، ول همراهت داري؟
No
نه
How you're gonna pay for it?
طوري ميخواي ولش رو حساب کني؟
I'm not
نميکنم
Well, I'm hungry
خب، من رسنه ام
Did you have to go and beat her up?
تو رفتي اون رو کتک زدي؟
I never beat 'er up
من هرز کتکش نزدم
You shagged her, though?
س، کرديش؟
No
نه
You don't believe me, do you?
باورت نميشه، نه؟
She's older than you
اون از تو بزرتره
Bollocks
مزخرفه
Poached egg.
تخم مرغ آب ز
That skirt's a bit short, innit, love?. 'T's disgraceful
اون دامن يکم کوتاهه، نه عزيزم؟ خجالت داره
What's this?
اين يه؟
That's where I'm gonna live
جايي که من ميرم زندي کنم
Where is it?
کجا هست؟
Ireland
ايرلند
I've lived in a cottage before
من قبلا تو يک کلبه زندي ميکردم
What, in one of your past lives?
کي؟ تو يکي از زندي هاي قبليت؟
Yes, as a matter of fact
آره، در حقيقت
Fuckin' shit-hole, innit?
سدونيه، نه؟
Don't waste your life
زنديت رو هدر نده
What?
ي؟
What time does this place close?
اينجا کي بسته ميشه؟
Four o'clock
ساعت هار
Listen, can you tell where I can get somethin' to eat round here?
ميتوني به من بي کجا اين اطراف ميتونم يزي بخورم؟
What?
ي؟
- You've got a very nice smile - 'Ave I?
لبخند دلنشيني داري جدا؟
Oh, yeah.
آره
Sorry, sir
ببخشيد قربان
I'll take that, sir.
من اين رو نه ميدارم قربان
Your lady companion's joinin' you, sir?
خانمتون بهتون ملحق ميشن قربان؟
No, - she can't make it today, pal, the old sciatica's
نه، امروز نميتونه، درد اعصاب داره
playin' up an' everything, you know?
خيلي خودنمايي ميکنه. ميفهمين؟
Come on
بيا
What?
کجا؟
Out the car
بيرون ماشين
But I've only just got in the car.
ولي من تازه سوار ماشين شدم
Get out of the fuckin' car!!!
مشو برو بيرون
All right Parker, keep your 'air on.
باشه ارکر، يک نفس عميق بکش
Well, that was lovely.
خب، دوست داشتني بود
Thank you
ممنون
Keep in touch
در تماس باش
Ooh, fuck
اوه
'Oo are you?
کي هستي؟
Sebastian Hawks.
سباستين هاکس
Nice to meet you
از ديدنت خوشبختم
Yeah, er, what're you doin' 'ere?
آهان، اينجا ي کار ميکني؟
I'm an acquaintance of Sandra's
من آشناي ساندرام
I've just popped round to say hallo
فتم بيام يه سلامي بکنم
Well, Sandra's away at the moment, actually
خب، ساندرا الان مسافرته، در واقع
Really? I hope you don't mind,
جدا؟ اميدوارم ناراحت نشين
but I helped myself to a beer
ولي من با يک آبجو از خودم ذيرايي کردم
Yeah, I noticed. Is that your champagne an' all?
آره، متوجه شدم. اون شاماين شماست؟
You like champagne, do you?
تو شاماين دوست داري، آره؟
Yeah. I do, as it 'appens.
آره، وقتي باشه
This is a very nice flat, don't you think?
اين خيلي آارتمان خوبيه، موافقي؟
'Ow'd you get in 'ere?
طوري داخل شدين؟
Tell me, d'you have any problems with the central heating?
بو ببينم، شما با سيستم حرارت مرکزي مشکلي دارين؟
Oh, are you the plumber?
اوه، شما لوله کشين؟
Let's just say I've got a vested interest in the property
فقط بم من علاقه ي وافري به املاک دارم
Fuckin' 'ell, you're the landlord.
اوه، شما صاحبخونه اين؟
I'd rather you thought of me as a friend
ترجيح ميدم رو من به عنوان يک دوست حساب کني
Oh shit!
اوه، لعنتي
What, is Sandra behind on the rent or somethin'?
خب، ساندرا اجاره اش رو به تعويق انداخته؟
Was your tattoo painful?
خالکوبيت دردناک بود؟
Yeah
آره
Good
خوبه
You're very beautiful, aren't you?
تو خيلي زيبايي، مه نه؟
Am I?
من؟
In a quirky sort of way.
يه جورايي عجيب غريبي
Are you a nurse?
رستاري؟
Yeah. Psychiatric.
آره، روانزشک
These are a very fetching pair of tights
اين جوراب هات خيلي جذابن
Ah, you like them, do yer, Mr Landlord?
اوه، شما دوستشون دارين آقاي صاحبخونه؟
Can we 'ave that champagne now, please?
ميتونيم الان شاماين بخوريم؟
Did you buy them
وقتي که اين رو خريدي همين شکلي بود
like this or are the holes self-inflicted?
يا اينکه سوراخ ها خودشون به وجود اومدن؟
No. A spider spun them, and that's where he 'ad a tea-break.
نه، عنکبوت اونا رو تنيده و اين برا وقتي هست که رفته بود اي بخوره
Fuckin' 'ell! That's a bit excessive, innit?
لعنتي! خيلي نده شد، نه؟
I rather like this belt too
من اين کمربند رو هم نسبتا دوست دارم
Oh, God! 'Ere we go.
واي خدا! شروع شد
Excuse me, where d'you think you're going?
ببخشيد، به نظرتون کجا دارين ميرين؟
I'm goin' home
ميرم خونه
What, are you leavin' me?
ي، من رو تنها ميذاري؟
I've come all this way to see you and you're goin'! I can't believe it,
من اين همه راه اومدم که شما رو ببينم بعد دارين ميرين خونه؟ باورم نميشه
I'm stunned, I'm flabbergasted.
شکه شدم، يج شدم
Shall we get you a tissue?
ميخواين بهتون دستمال بدم
Sounds promisin'. Do you live nearby?
اميد بخشه. اين نزديکي ها زندي ميکني؟
I might do.
شايد
I mean, is it within walking distance?
منظورم اينه که مسافت در حد ياده رويه؟
No, 'cause you see, I've got this fascination with all things peripatetic.
ميدوني، ون من به کارهاي درويش مآبانه خيلي علاقه مندم
See you!
ميبينمت
I'm cheeky, aren't I?
من ستاخم، نه؟
Have you stolen the teacosy? Love, people can see you wearin' that thing,
تو در قوري رو دزديدي؟ عزيزم مردم ميبينن که اين رو وشيدي
are you not embarassed? No?
خجالت نميکشي؟ نه؟
Don't give up
ادامه بده
Put this on!
اين رو تنت کن
Oh, what? We're gonna play doctors and nurses now, are we?
اوه، ي؟ ميخوايم دکتر و رستار بازي کنيم؟
Hurry up!
عجله کن
Oh, this is ridiculous.
اوه، مزحکه
Listen, I'm really sorry, right?
وش کن، من واقعا متاسفم
But I've had a bit of a rough week,
ولي من هفته ي سختي رو شت سر ذاشتم
and I just don't think I can go through with this
و فکر نميکنم که بتونم اين کار رو بکنم
Oh, no! No!
اوه، نه! نه
Fuck off! leave me alove! No!
ورت رو م کن، تنهام بذار! نه
You fuckin' bastard!!
مادر قحبه
D'you want some beans?
يکم عرق ميخواي؟
Yeah, cheers.
آره، به سلامتي
So, what would you be doin' now if I wasn't 'ere?
خب، الان اه من نبودم ي کار ميکردي؟
Dunno
نميدونم
Having a shower, relaxin'
دوش ميرفتم، استراحت ميکردم
I could do with a shower myself
من هم ميتونم دوش بيرم؟
I haven't washed for about a week
من يه هفته است خودم رو نشستم
As you've probably noticed
احتمالا بايد متوجه شده باشي
Well, you can 'ave one if you like
خب، اه دوست داري اشکال نداره
Are you sure?
مطمئني؟
Yeah. Bathroom's just here
آره، حموم اينجاست
Fuckin' 'ell
لعنتي
What did I do to deserve you, love?
من ي کار کردم که لايق تو باشم عزيزم؟
Just press this button
فقط اين دکمه رو فشار بده
Now listen
حالا وش کن
You're not going to creep up on me with a big knife dressed up as your mother, are you?
تو که با يک اقو، در حالي که مثل مادرت لباس وشيدي دنبال من نميخزي؟ ها؟
No.
نه
Although it looks like you already are dressed up as your mother
اره به نظر ميرسه که در حال حاضر مثل مادرت لباس وشيدي
Can I have me bag?
ميتونم کيفم رو بردارم؟
It's got me duck in it.
اردکم توشه
Ta
مرسي
Oh dear
اوه عزيزم
'Oo lives 'ere, then? Zeus?
س کي اينجا زندي ميکنه؟ زئوس؟
Is all this stuff yours?
اينا همش براي توئه؟
No.
نه
All these pseudo-Doric midgets
تمام اين خرت و رت هاي کاذب دوريسي
with their novelty underpants
با اين زيرشلواري هاي نو ظهورشون
Oh, look at this one, touchin' time with a bargepole
اوه، اين رو ناه کن که به زمان هم اهميت ميده
I wouldn't
من که نميدم
Is 'e a home-owner-sexual, yeah?
صاحبخونه همجنس راست؟
What do you think?
تو ي فکر ميکني؟
Where is 'e?
کجاست؟
They're in America
اونا آمريکان
They?
اونا؟
Yeah.
آره
When are they gettin' back?
اونا کي بر ميردن؟
Dunno
نميدونم
And they're just letting you stop 'ere, for nothin, yeah?
و اونوقت به تو اجازه ميدن همينجوري اينجا بموني؟
Yeah. I don't know them
من نميشناسمشون
I don't know, I find this all a bit sad
نميدونم، اينا يکم به نظر من دردناک ميان
Why?
را؟
No, I don't mean that to sound homophobic
نه، حرفم هموفوبيک نبود
I mean, I like The Iliad
يعني، من ايلياد رو دوست دارم
and The Odyssey. D'you get that?
و اوديسه، ميفهمي؟
No
نه
So, 'ave you read many of these books?
خب، تو تعداد زيادي از اين کتاب ها رو خوندي؟
No, I haven't.
نه، نخوندم
Oh, I've read quite a few
من خيلي هاش رو خوندم
Oh, look!
اوه، ناه کن
D'you get it now?
اينو به ياد مياري؟
D'you know this?
ميدوني اين يه؟
I bet you do. You've most likely done it at school
مطمئنم که ميدوني. تو احتمالا اين رو تو مدرسه خوندي
You just can't remember
فقط يادت نمياد
You know, like, Achilles' heel
مثلا مثل نقطه ي جراحت ذير آريليس
the Wooden Horse, Helen of Troy. You know them?
اسب وبي، هلن تروي ميشناسيشون؟
Yeah.
آره
yeah, well, that's all it is.
خب، خوبه، همش همينه
Good stuff. Cyclops.
يز خوبيه. غول يک شم
Oh, hallo,
اوه سلام
it's Pizza Deliveryman
اين يک يتزاست؟
D'you want those beans?
عرقه رو نميخواي؟
Oh, yeah, I forgot
اوه، آره، يادم رفته بود
Sebastian Hawks. Good evening.
سباستين هاکس، عصر بخير
Very nice to meet you, Louise.
از ديدنتون خيلي خوشحالم، لوئيس
Oh, very nice to meet you
اوه، خوشحالم از ديدنتون
I've heard a lot about you
من زياد راجع بهتون شنيدم
Sophie?
سوفي؟
Yeah? Yeah, I'm in 'ere
هان؟ بله؟ من اينجام
- Oh, are you all right? - I've never been better
اوه، تو حالت خوبه؟
We've had a very interesting afternoon, haven't we, Sophie?
ما بعد از ظهر خيلي خوبي داشتيم. مه نه سوفي؟
It's been fascinatin'!
محشر بود
For services rendered
براي خدمات ارائه داده شده
Fuck off!
برو مشو
'Oo's your friend?
اين رفيقت کيه؟
'E's the landlord, in''e?
صاحبخونه
'Oose landlord?
صاحبخونه کيه؟
Our fuckin' landlord
صاحبخونه ي لعنتي ما
- Oh, get out o'town! - Ask 'im
اوه، اشتباه ميکني از خودش برس
What you wearin' Sandra's uniform for?
برا ي يونيفرم ساندرا رو وشيدي؟
I don't want to talk about it, all right?
نميخوام راجع بهش صحبت کنم، باشه؟
Well, d'you wanna cup o'tea?
خب، يه فنجون اي ميخوري؟
Yeah
آره
So,'ave you been sittin' on 'is face all afternoon?
س، تمام بعد از ظهر رو صورتش نشسته بودي؟
I don't need this
بس کن
Jesus Christ, I get 'ome from work,
اوه، من از سر کار ميام خونه
all I want to do is to put me feet up and watch the telly,
و تمام کارهايي که ميخوام بکنم اينه که ام رو دراز کنم و تلويزيون ببينم
not get involved in one of your orgies. D'you know what I mean?
نه اين که درير عشق و حال تو بشم. ميفهمي ي ميم؟
What 'appened to your arm?
بازوت ي شده؟
Sophie, what's been goin' on?
سوفي، اينجا ه خبر بود؟
Have you put the kettle on?
کتري رو ذاشتي؟
Yeah
آره
Any chance of a coffee, Louise?
ممکنه قهوه بخوريم لوئيس؟
Yeah, sure
آره، حتما
These are a very nice pair of shorts
ه زيرشلواري قشني
Would you take your 'ands off me, please?
ميشه لطفا دستت رو بکشي؟
I apologise
معذرت ميخوام
Right, pal. 'Ere's your clothes, get your kit on and sling yer 'ook.
خب، رفيق اينا لباسهاته، کول شتيت رو بر دار و فلن رو ببند
'Ere's your shoes, mate
اينم کفشهات
Hope I haven't given you AIDS, Sophie.
اميدوارم بهت ايدز منتقل نکرده باشم
- Jesus Christ - Fuckin' 'ell!! Are you serious?
يا مسيح لعنتي! جدي ميي؟
Merely jesting.
صرفا يک مزاح بود
Very funny.
خيلي بانمک بود
Mind you, I think AIDS is rather healthy in its way.
وش کن، به نظر من ايدز هم به نوبه ي خودش سالمه
You what?
ي؟
I realize that's not the fashionable thing to say, of course.
ميفهمم، شيک نيست اين حرف ها البته
No. It's not.
نه، نيست
But the world is overcrowded, isn't it? It could do with a bit of pruning.
ولي جمعيت دنيا بيش از حده، نه؟ اين ميتونه تا حدودي کمش کنه
Fuckin' better be jokin'.
بهتره حرفت شوخي باشه
You're not going to have children, are you, Louise?
تو نميخواي به دار بشي، ميخواي لوئيس؟
I might do, one day.
ممکنه يک روز بخوام
I loathe children, I must say
من بايد بم که از به ها متنفرم
I bet they're not too keen on you, neither
شرط ميبندم اونا هم علاقه ي زيادي به تو ندارن
- I'm sure you like fucking, don't you, Louise? - Are you goin'?
من مطمئنم که تو اييدن رو دوست داري، نه لوئيس؟ داري ميري؟
I'm rather enjoying myself, actually
نسبتا داره بهم خوش ميذره
- Well, we're not - That's a pity
خب، به ما نميذره ه بد
Look, you may be the landlord from hell, but that doesn't give you the right to lie on our couch
ناه کن، تو ممکنه صاحب خونه ي جهنم باشي ولي اين حق رو نداري که روي مبل ما دراز بکشي
Whose couch?
مبل کي؟
D'you want me to phone the police?
ميخواي به ليس زن بزنم؟
Be my guest
مهمون من باش
Right
باشه
- Listen, I can't 'ave them in 'ere? - Why not?
وش کن، من نميتونم اونها رو اينجا راه بدم را نميتوني؟
They gonna take one look at 'im in 'is suit and one look at us
اونا ميان يک ناه به لباس اون ميندازن و يک ناه به ما
and 'oo d'you think they're gonna believe?
و تو فکر ميکني که باور ميکنن؟
There's fuckin' dope all over the place
خونه ر از مواده
Well, we're just windin' him up - 'e's loving this.
خب، ما فقط اون رو تحريکش ميکنيم اون، اين رو دوست داره
What are we gonna do?
ي کار ميخواهيم بکنيم؟
It's very peaceful in 'ere, isn't it?
اينجا خيلي آرومه، نه؟
I suppose so
مان ميکنم اينطور باشه
Are you warm enough?
به اندازه ي کافي رمت هست؟
Yeah, this is nice - thanks
آره، خوبه. ممنون
It's funny, 'cos the silence usually freaks me out
جالبه، سکوت معمولا حال من رو خراب ميکنه
You start to pick up on all the small sounds,
تو شروع کن يه صداي آرومي از خودت دربياري
you know what I mean? Like that clock
ميدوني منظورم يه؟ مثل اون ساعت
I hate that fuckin' clock
من از اون ساعت متنفرم
Of course you do - it's a clock
معلومه که متنفري، اون يک ساعته
Is it all right if I stay here
اشکال نداره اه من امشب
tonight?
اينجا بمونم؟
'Ve you ever 'ad
تا حالا
a dog?
يک س داشتي؟
No.
نه
I don't like dogs
من س ها رو دوست ندارم
Why?
را؟
Well, they're either vicious or daft
خب، اونا هم بدطينت و هم در عين حال خرفتن
- Why, 'ave you? - Yeah
طور؟ تو داشتي؟ آره
Is it dead now?
الان مرده؟
Did you bury it?
دفنش کردي؟
I dunno, me dad took it
نميدونم، بابام بردش
And what about you? Would you like to be buried or cremated?
تو ي؟ دوست داري دفن بشي و خاکسترت رو بسوزنن؟
I couldn't give a shit
اهميت نميدم
I 'ad this dream the other night, about these two skeletons 'aving a fuck.
من اين رويا رو يک شب، در مورد
It was a right bloody racket - woke me up.
دو تا اسکلت در حال کردن همديه داشتم يک راکت خوني بود که من رو بيدار کرد
'Ave you got a photo of your mum?
عکسي از مامانت داري؟
What, on me?
ي، همراهم؟
Yeah
آره
No
نه
But I think you might find one over at the newsagent's, on the top shelf
ولي فکر کنم، يکي توي مجله ي ورنورافي بتوني ير بياري
D'you want some beans?
عرق ميخوري؟
You've got a very sad face
تو صورت خيلي ناراحتي داري
'Ave I?
آره؟
It's all right, I mean,
اشکال نداره، منظورم اينه که
I find that attractive
به نظر من جذابه
But that's me
ولي خب اين نظر منه
So, 'ave you got a boyfriend or anythin'?
دوست سري، يزي داري؟
What are gonna do for Christmas?
برا کريسمس ي کار ميکني؟
I don't know. What're you gonna do?
نميدونم، تو ي؟
You all right?
تو حالت خوبه؟
What's the matter?
موضوع يه؟
Fuck off!
مشو
What's up love?
ي شده عزيزم؟
Was it something I said?
من يزي فتم؟
I want you to go
من ميخوام که بري
Why?
را؟
Can you go, please?!
ميشه لطف کني، بري؟
Is it 'cos I don't like dogs?
به اين دليل که من س ها رو دوست ندارم؟
Get out!!
برو بيرون
I don't quite follow, love
من درست نميفهمم عزيزم
Just fuck off!!
فقط مشو
Oh, I see
اوه، رفتم
Well, perhaps I was jumpin' to conclusions, but I got the impression I could kip down on the sofa or somethin'
شايد من زود قضاوت کردم ولي اينطوري برداشت ميکنم که ميتونم روي کاناه اي، يزي، بخوابم
- Go! - Go where?
برو کجا برم؟
'Ave you got any suggestions? 'Cos it's like
تو يشنهادي داري؟ ون
a fuckin' Eskimo's grave out there.
اون بيرون مثل قبر يک اسکيمو ميمونه
All right, I'm going
باشه، من ميرم
It's not easy, is it?
راحت نيست، هست؟
D'you find that?
ميفهمي؟
Well, just goes to show you
خب، فقط ميرم که نشونت بدم
that no matter how many books you read,
که مهم نيست قدر کتاب خوندي
there's some things in this world that you never, ever, ever, ever,
يک يزهايي توي اين دنيا هست که هرز، هرز
ever fuckin' understand.
هرز، نخواهي فهميد
Thank you for the tea, and the bath,
ممنون بابت اي و حموم
and the booze.
و مشروب
And the beans.
و عرق
And listen love,
و وش کن عزيز
I hope that when you're tucked up tonight
من اميدوارم وقتي امشب لاي تو رم و نرمت
all snug and warm underneath your tear-sodden fuckin' duvet
که در اثر اشک هات روک شده، خوابيدي
and your ankle-length Emily Bronte windin'-sheet
و با قوزک ات داري ملافه رو ماله ميکني
that you spare a thought for me, with my head in a puddle of cold dog's piss,
ياد من بي افتي که توي ه س خوابيدم
An' I hope that you dream about me.
و من اميدوارم خواب من رو ببيني
An' I hope that you wake up screaming.
و اميدوارم که درحال جيغ زدن بيدار شي
And I hope that all your fuckin' children
و اميدوارم تمام به هاي هت
are born blind, bow-legged, hare-lipped, homeless hunchbacks!!
کور و کج ا و وژشت به دنيا بيان
'Ave you ever 'ad an abortion?
تا حالا سقط کردي؟
'Ave you?
تو کردي؟
No. I thought I was pregnant once.
نه، يک بار فکر ميکردم که حامله ام
Would you 'ave 'ad one?
دوست داري يکي داشته باشي؟
Will, In the end, it turned out I wasn't, and 'e left me anyway, so...
خب، آخرش ميذاره من رو ول ميکنه و ميره در هر صورت
I wanted to keep mine
من ميخوام مال خودم رو نه دارم
What happened?
ي شده؟
All my mates said I couldn't look after a baby
همه ي دوستام فتن که من نميتونم از يک به مراقبت کنم
Too fuckin' right.
کاملا حق دارن
Did it make you feel shitty?
اين اعصابت رو به هم ميريزه؟
It was a nightmare.
کابوس بود
I really loved 'im
من واقعا عاشقش بودم
'E was a philosopher
اون يک فيلسوف بود
Where was this?
کجا بود؟
Paris.
اريس
You should've seen the state of 'is girlfriend
تو بايد حال دوست دخترش رو ميديدي
'Ad one when I was fifteen, an' all.
فقط يک بار وقتي که انزده سالم بود، همش همين
Oh, Jesus, Sophie!
اوه، سوفي
I think that one was worse for my mum,
فکر ميکنم براي مادرم بدتر بود
fuckin' drama she made out of it
ه نمايشينامه اي ازش درست کرد
I could've been married by now, with a four-year-old
من الان ميتونم با يک هار ساله هم ازدواج کنم
D'you want to get married?
ميخواي ازدواج کني؟
Don't know
نميدونم
Just 'cos you 'ave a kid with someone doesn't mean they're gonna stick around.
اين که فقط با يکي ديه به دار بشي معنيش اين نيست که دور و برت بمونن
My dad didn't. 'E couldn't fuckin' wait to get out.
باباي من اين کار رو نکرد. نتونست براي اينکه بزنه بيرون، صبر کنه
Well, don't know if I want to get married,
خب، منم مطمئن نيستم که بخوام ازدواج کنم
but I wouldn't say no to a proper relationship
ولي از طرف ديه به يک رابطه ي مناسب هم نه نميم
What is a proper relationship?
اين رابطه ي مناسب ي هست؟
Livin' with someone 'oo talks to you after they've bonked you.
با يکي زندي کني که بعد از اينکه کردت، باهات حرف بزنه
I don't know what they want from you 'alf the time.
من بعضي وقت ها نميفهمم که اونها ازت ي ميخوان
What they start off liking you for
در آخر به همون دليلي که بهت علاقه يدا کردن
they end up hatin' you for.
ازت متنفر ميشن
Don't like you if you're strong, don't like you if you're weak;
اه قوي باشي دوستت ندارن اه ضعيف باشي دوستت ندارن
hate you if you're clever, hate you if you're stupid.
متنفرن ازت اه باهوش باشي متنفرن ازت اه احمق باشي
They don't know what they want.
خودشون هم نميدونن ي ميخوان
D'you think that bastard's fucked off yet?
فکر ميکني تا الان اون حرومزاده ورش رو م کرده باشه؟
Yeah, he musta done by now.
آره، تا الان ديه بايد اين کار رو کرده باشه
Is this a stick-up?
اين عکس مجرمه؟
- Sorry - you must get that all the time, yeah? - Yeah
ببخشيد - شما هميشه اين کار رو ميکنين؟ آره
Just got it again.
يک دونه ديه
So is this your job, or a nice little hobby you've got for yourself?
خب، اين شغلته يا فقط يه سررمي کوک که برا خودت دست و ا کردي؟
You're a lovely mover!
خيلي قشن تکون ميخوري
- This your van, yeah? - Yeah
اين ون توئه، آره؟ آره
It's like, er, I dunno, top o' the range.
به نظر مياد که، نميدونم، بهترين مدلش باشه
Very nice
خيلي خوبه
Are you goin' up the road?
جاده رو ميري بالا؟
D'you wanna lift?
ميخواي برسونمت؟
Is that all right with you?
برا تو مشکلي نداره؟
Cheers
مرسي
It's just, I've been walkin' round the streets all night, you know what I mean?
آخه من کل شب داشتم خيابون ها رو بالا و ايين ميکردم، ميفهمي ي ميم؟
These fuckin' feet are on their last legs, I'm telling you.
در اين حد بهت بم که اهام رو به موتن
So, 'ow much d'you earn for doin' this?
خب، قدر براي اين کار در مياري؟
It's none of your fuckin' business
به تو مربوط نيست
I mean, is the pay as substantial as say, the wages of sin?
منظورم اينه که مزدت همون اندازه اي (wages of sin)هست که مين، مزد ناه؟
You know what I mean? Are you with me?
ميفهمي ي ميم؟ حواست به منه؟
Listen, Captain, is it all right if I 'ave a go at doin' this, yeah?
وش کن کايتان، اشکال نداره که من اين کار رو بکنم؟
Oh! God love you!
اوه، خداي من
I mean, or does it take like thousands of years of like
منظورم اينه که، هزاران سال طول ميکشه که
state-subsidized government training to do this clobber, yeah?
حقوق بيراي دولت بخوان اين کار رو بکنن
You've gotta slap on like copious quantities
You've gotta slap on like copious quantities
of the old industrial sputum there.
of the old industrial sputum there.
Beg your puddin'
عذر ميخوام
It's a wonderful career opportunity for me -
اين براي من يک موقعيت شغلي فوق العاده است
you know what I mean? I'm not gonna play the joker on this one.
ميفهمي ي ميم؟
- Shift - It's all goin' very well
برو کنار همه ي داره خوب يش ميره
Shift out the fuckin' way, will you?
برو کنار از سر راه، خب؟
No, I like Laurel and Hardy, you know, although apparently they didn't get on in real life,
نه، من لورل و هاردي رو دوست دارم، ميفهمي، اره ظاهرا هي وقت تو زندي واقعيشون به جايي نميرسن
You know, another illusion shattered.
ميدوني، يک حباب توهمِ ديه که ميترکه
Sorry about that pal, it's just I've 'ad a lot of bad experience with walls,
شرمنده رفيق، من تجربه هاي تلخي از ديوار دارم
you know, what with talking to them and climbing them,
ميفهمي، به دليل حرف زدن و بالا رفتن ازشون
and me dad's driven me up a good few of them in 'is time, you know what I mean?
بابام قديم ها من رو از ندتاشون بالا برده بود ميفهمي ي ميم؟
But I think I've got the secret. The saucy little secret,
ولي من فکر ميکنم يک رازي دارم. يک راز کوک
this solipsistic, sagacious little secret is just, you got - you just gotta
اين راز نفس رايانه ي هوشمندانه اينه که فقط
bang your fuckin' head against them!
سرت رو به ديوار بکوبي
Just crack the old pate.
فقط کله رو بشکوني
Are you with me?! 'Ave you got it?
حواست به منه؟ فهميدي ي شد؟
And that's it, that's the key to enlightenment, which is, it's like that's why,
و اينه، اين رمز روشنريه که، به خاطر اينه که
it's like such a potent motif of civilization - it's the wall.
شبيه يک اصل مدنيه اين ديواره
It's like the, the Great Wall of China, and the Wall of Jericho
مثل ديوار بزر ين، ديوار جريکو
and the Berlin Wall, and the Wailin' Wall
و ديوار برلين و ديوار ندبه
Now you see the Jews, they've almost got it, an't they?
حالا يهودي ها رو ببين، اونا تقريبا دارنش، نه؟
What with the old rockin' and that, and you know, just that six inches away
اون صخره ي قديمي و، ميدوني، فقط 6 اين اونورتر
and they'd be there, they'd have won the fuckin' race, they'll be there, you with me?
و اونا اونجا مي مونن، اونها توي اين رقابت لعنتي يروز ميشن اونا اونجا مي مونن، حواست به منه؟
What is all this, anyway? What are you doin'? Cancel everythin'.
اين ها معنيش يه؟ ي کار ميکني؟ همه يز رو کنسل ميکني؟
In the beginnin' there was the Word, and the word was 'cancelled'
در ابتدا يک کلمه وجود داشت، و اون کلمه "کنسل" بود
D'you get like satisfaction out of this? D'you think you're makin' a contribution?
تو با اين کارها راضي ميشي؟ فکر ميکني که داري يک جور همکاري ميکني؟
You're like sort of publicly promulgatin' vacuities? Are you with me?
تو مثلا يک جور اعلان عمومي وي ها هستي؟ حواست به منه؟
Fuckin' hell!!
لعنتي
Oh, that's it! Blank it all out! Blank it all out
همينه ديه! فراموش کن! فراموش کن
till you just atrophy and die of fuckin' indifference.
تا بوسي و بميري از اين بي ميلي لعنتي
Can I show you somethin', pal? You see that at the top of your legs?
ميتونم يک يزي بهت نشون بدم؟ تو اون رو بالاي اهات ميبيني؟
That's your arse and that's your fuckin' elbow! Do you want to write it down or s-
اون کونته و اون آرنج لعنتيت، ميخواي ثبتش کني يا
'Oo's that supposed to be, me dad?
فکر کرده کيه؟ بابام؟
You wanna watch that, mate - I've got a dicky sacrum 'ere
ميخواي ناه کني رفيق من يک استخوان خاجي کيري اينجا دارم
Shit!
ه
Can you come back here? Did I upset you?
ميشه برردي؟ عصبانيت کردم؟
You've got me bag! You fuckin' tosser!!
کيفم رو بردي! جلقي کثافت
You f-
تو
Fuck!!
ه
Oh, listen!! Does anybody mind if I scream 'ere?
وش کنين! کسي اهميت ميده که من اينجا عربده بزنم؟
Is that OK with you all? 'Cos I'd feel better
شما رو ناراحت نميکنه؟ ون حال من رو بهتر ميکنه
for it - won't take long!
زياد طول نميشکه
Fuck
لعنتي
'Os's that?
کيه؟
Oh Jesus!
اوه خداي من
What's been happenin' to you?
ه بلايي سرت اومده؟
Will you shut up, for God's sake?
تو رو به خدا، ميشه ساکت باشي؟
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry
ببخشيد، ببخشيد، ببخشيد
Just give us a fag
فقط يه سيار بده
Fuckin' comedian
دلقک لعنتي
- It's not my fault - What's not your fault?
تقصير من نبود ي تقصير تو نبود؟
Where are you goin'?
کجا داري ميري؟
I just want to go to bed
فقط ميخوام برم بخوابم
Be quiet!
آروم
I fuckin' walked 'ere
تا اينجا ياده اومدم
Where from?
از کجا؟
Johnny.
جاني
I'm gonna be sick
داره حالم به هم ميخوره
Fuckin' 'ell, what's 'appened to 'im?
اوه، ش شده؟
I dunno
نميدونم
Johnny, are you all right, Johnny?
جاني، تو حالت خوبه؟
Get off!
برو کنار
Is 'e still 'ere?
اون هنوز اينجاست؟
I dunno
نميدونم
Right, we'd better get him into bed
خب، بهتره ببريمش رو تخت
You take that end, I'll take this end
تو اون سرش رو بير، من هم اين سرش
OK, don't push me, right?
خب، هلم نده
I'm not pushin' you!
من هلت نميدم
Careful, that's 'is bad leg
مراقب باش، اين اشه که در رفته
Well, what d'you want me to do?
خب، ميخواي ي کار کنم؟
After three
بعد سه شماره
One, two, three
يک، دو ، سه
I wanna go!
من ميخوام برم
I know
ميدونم
I know, you told me
تو به من فتي، ميدونم
I'm not here yet. I'm still wet
من اينجا نيستم. من هنوز مستم
What did she mean?
منظورش يه؟
Why not me brother?
را من نه برادر؟
Will it be quiet now?
الان آروم ميشه؟
Are we goin'?
ما ميريم؟
Fuck!
لعنتي
Who's this?
اين کيه؟
It's all right, 'e's a friend of mine
مشکلي نيست، دوست منه
What extraordinary friends you have. He's only got one sock on.
عجب دوستان شفت انيزي داري تو يارو فقط يک جوراب اشه
Shut up!
خفه شو
You seem a bit tense, Sophie. Would you like a massage?
يکم عصباني به نظر مياي سوفي، يکم ماساژ ميخواي؟
Are you the doctor?
تو دکتري؟
Pardon?
ببخشيد؟
Is he the doctor?
اين دکتره؟
You're rather disgusting, aren't you?
تو نفرت انيزي، نه؟
You're not crying, are you, Louise?
تو که ريه نميکني لوئيس؟
Oh, listen, when are you gonna fuck off?
او، وش کن، کي ميخواي ورت رو م کني؟
This 'as got nothin' to do with you, right?
اين هي کاري با تو نداره، ميفهمي؟
No! No!
نه، نه
Leave me alone!
ولم کن
Fuckin' 'ell, me leg!
لعنتي، ام
You don't know
نمي فهمي
Aren't people pathetic?
مردم رقت انيز نيستن؟
Right. I'm going to beddy-byes.
خب، من ميرم بخوابم
If anyone wishes to join me, I'll be under the duvet
اه کسي خواست به من بيونده، من زير تو هستم
Are you all right?
تو حالت خوبه؟
Yeah. Are you?
آره، تو ي؟
Yeah.
اوهوم
Come on, I'll give you a hand.
اشو، دستت رو بده من
I'm all right, I walked 'ere.
من حالم خوبه، تا اينجا ياده اومدم
Is it 'ere?
اينجاست؟
Yeah.
آره
'Oo's that?
کي هست؟
Clancy.
کلانسي
I thought so.
فکرش رو ميکردم
I used to know you, didn't I?
ميشناسمت نه؟
Yeah.
آره
"Take me back to Manchester
"Take me back to Manchester
when it's raining.
when it's raining.
I want to wet me feet in Albert Square.
I want to wet me feet in Albert Square.
I'm all agog For a good, thick fog.
I'm all agog For a good, thick fog.
I don't like the sun,
I don't like the sun,
I like it raining cats and dogs!
I like it raining cats and dogs!
I want to smell the odours of the Irwell.
I want to smell the odours of the Irwell.
I want to feel the soot get in me 'air,
I want to feel the soot get in me 'air,
Oh, I don't want to roam.
Oh, I don't want to roam.
I want to get back 'ome
I want to get back 'ome
to rainy Manchester"
to rainy Manchester"
I've got an 'ard-on.
من شق کردم
What's...?
ي؟
What are you...?
شما ي...؟
This is...It's disgusting!
اين...نفرت انيزه
Nobody, in my....
هيکس...توي
Who's 'e?
اين کيه؟
You've got your boots on! She's...
تو کفش هات اته!
And what's this doing?
و اين اينجا ي کار ميکنه؟
This is something I can't... I don't....
اين يزيه که من نميتونم من نبايد
It's not...I just don't need all this...palaver.
من فقط ديه به اين هرزه ويي ها... احتياجي ندارم
Oh, shit!
اوه، لعنتي
Ok, who's Jeremy ?
خب، جرمي کيه؟
- Who's Jeremy ? - What you mean?
جرمي کيه؟ منظورت يه؟
Sandra! What a nice surprise!
ساندرا! غافليرم کردي
What are you doing here?
تو اينجا ي کار ميکني؟
How was Zimbabwe?
زيمباوه طور بود؟
Shift!
کنار
Morning, Louise.
صبح به خير لوئيس
- Where's Jeremy ? - 'Oo's Jeremy ?
جرمي کجاست؟ جرمي کيه؟
These are Jeremy's
اينا براي جرميه
That's Sebastian's.
اينا برا سباستينه
No, look. Jeremy Smart. Jeremy Smart. Jeremy G. Smart.
نه ناه کن جرمي اسمارت، جرمي اسمارت، جرمي ج اسمارت
Well, I've never 'eard of him.
خب، من يزي راجع بهش نميدونم
Sebastian. Who - Are you Jeremy G. Smart ?
سباستين. کي تو جرمي ج اسمارتي؟
Are you?
هستي؟
Johnny! Johnny, wake up
جاني! جاني، بيدار شو
Just leave 'im
ولش کن
Oh, for fuck's sake, Sophie, Sandra's back.
اوه خواهش ميکنم، سوفي، ساندرا برشته
- What day is it? - It's Friday
ند شنبه است؟ جمعه
Fuck this
لعنتي
Look at 'is eye
شم هاش رو ناه کن
Christ
خداي من
Well, he can lie down in my room - oh, God!
خب، ميتونه تو اطاق من دراز بکشه، واي خدا
What're you doin'? 'E's not 'arming anyone
ي کار ميکني؟ اون به کسي آسيبي نميرسونه
'Ave you seen the state of 'er?
حالش رو نميبيني؟
- Johnny! - I'm here, Johnny
جاني من اينجام جاني
Morning, everyone
صبح به خير به همي
I would, actually, like to have some kind of
من در واقع، به يک سري توضيحات
explanation for all this, because...
در باره ي اين قضايا احتياج دارم، ون
- Having fun? - Can you put these on, please?
خوش ذشت؟ ميشه لطف کني اين رو بيوشي؟
Sophie and I had a fuck on your bed yesterday afternoon, Sandra.
من و سوفي ديروز رو تخت تو همدير رو اييديم، ساندرا
- She was very good, I must say - You are just...filth! - Not as good as you, though
بايد اعتراف کنم که اون خيلي خوب بود ولي اره نه به خوبي تو
You lying...nastiness!
تو دروغ ميي... کثافت
We must do it again sometime
ما بايد دوباره اين کار رو بکنيم
Will you...?
ميشه...؟
How can you...?
طور تونستين...؟
Everything!
همه ي رو
I can't cope with this
من نميتونم با اين کنار بيام
You've got five minutes
نج دقيقه وقت داري
Five minutes to get your things on and get the hell...
نج دقيقه که وسايلت رو جمع کني و بري به جهنم
I shouldn't worry about things so much, if I were you
من اه جاي تو بودم خيلي به اين يزها اهميت نميدادم
I'd forgotten what a beautiful bottom you've got, Sandra
يادم رفته بود که ه باسن خوشلي داري ساندرا
Two minutes
دو دقيقه
Marvellous tits!
ممه هاي شفت انيز
Listen, Sandra, I'm really sorry. We weren't expectin' you back.
وش کن ساندرا، من واقعا متاسفم اصلا انتظار نداشتيم که تو برردي
I fail to...why...
من نتونستم... را
It's a pigsty ... it's...
اينجا خوکدونيه... اينجا
I know - it just got out of hand
ميدونم... همه ي به هم ريخته
Obviously. And what's all that?
کاملا مشخصه. و اونها ي؟
'E's a friend of mine - Look, can I make you a cup o'tea?
اون دوست منه،ببين، من ميتونم يک فنجون اي برات درست کنم
I don't want tea... I don't want...
من اي نميخوام... نميخوام
I just want...  My journey was...
من فقط... مسافرتم
He's not very well!
اون حالش خوب نيست
What's the matter with 'im?
مشکلش يه؟
'E's got a lump on his face the size of a boiled egg an' 'he won't wake up
صورتش به اندازه ي يک تخم مرغ آبز باد کرده و بيدار نميشه
Did he do this?
اون اين کار رو کرده؟
- 'Oo ? - Sebastian - Jeremy?
کي؟ سباستين، جرمي؟
You never warned me about 'im, did you?
تو هي وقت راجع به اون به من هشدار نداده بودي، داده بودي؟
What are you talking about?
راجع به ي داري صحبت ميکني؟
Fuckin' lettin' 'imself in with the keys! Bastard!
کثافت خودش با کليد اومد تو خونه حرومزاده
I don't...
من نميفهمم
Right. Let's get
خب. بيا
this shoe off.
اين کفشش رو در بياريم
Have you ever had smoked salmon after making love, Louise?
تا حالا بعد از عشق بازي ماهي دودي خوردي، لوئيس؟
Don't like smoked salmon
ماهي دودي دوست ندارم
I think you should try it. It's rather wonderful.
فکر کنم بايد امتحانش کني ميشه فت فوق العاده است
Will you undo your flies, Sebastian?
رواز هات رو کنسل ميکني، سباستين؟
Would you like me to?
دوست داري اين کار رو بکنم؟
Honest.
واقعا آره
Or d'you not want me to slice your prick off and shove it up your arse?
نميخواهي که دولت رو ببرم و بکنمش تو کونت؟
Maggot dick!
کير کوولو
Could you pass me that pillow, please?
ميشه لطفا اون بالش رو بدي به من؟
- I can't move, Sandra - Here you go
من نميتونم تکون بخورم ساندرا بيا
You are worse than useless
تو از به درد نخوري هم ذشتي
Ooh, are y'all right? You don't think it's broken, do you?
اوه، حالت خوبه؟ فکر نميکني که شکسته باشه، ها؟
No, 'e can move it.
نه، ميتونه تکونش بده
You can do that, can't you?
تو ميتوني اين کار رو بکني، نه؟
Why would I want to do that?
را از من ميخواي اين کار رو بکنم؟
Don't even... Not in my room, Sophie.
تو اطاق من نه سوفي؟
I need a fag
من سيار لازم دارم
I don't care. Cop hold o'that.
به من ربطي نداره. اين رو نه دار
Just don't start, right?
دوباره شروع نکن، خب؟
It really is beyond me the way you girls choose to live your lives
واقعا براي من اين شيوه ي زندي که شما دخترا واسه ي خودتون انتخاب کردين غير قابل تصوره
My mind just boggles
من که من شدم
'E's gone back to sleep
دوباره خوابش برد
Was that the front door?
در اصلي بود
'E's gone
رفت
Thank God
خدا رو شکر
Go slowly, Johnny.
آروم بيا جاني
Now what you two must do is take this one to Casualty
حالا فقط تنها کاري که بايد بکنين اينه که ببرينش به بخش سوانح
and make sure he gets himself looked at, 'fore he goes home.
و مطمئن بيشين که خودش رو نشون بده، قبل از اينکه بره خونه
I'm gonna be sick.
داره حالم بهم ميخوره
- Are you? - Get him into the bathroom!
جدا؟ ببرش تو حموم
All right! Let's not...
باشه
Just a minute...
يک دقيقه صبر کن
That's it.
خودشه
- Take it steady. - Here y'are
اين رو محکم بير
It's in me tash.
تو سبيل هامه
You wanna gerrit cut.
بايد کوتاهشون کني
It's in your mouth
تو دهنته
'Ave you 'ad a bath lately?
اخيرا حموم بودي؟
Yeah, I 'ad one yesterday
آره، ديروز
- As if! - I did!
معلومه خب بودم
Where've you been, Johnny?
کجا بودي جاني؟
Down the Via Dolorosa.
ايين ويا دولوروسا
Don't be nosy
فضولي نکن
- Are you not goin' to work? - I'm late
نميري سر کار؟ دير کردم
Oh, you'll get the sack
اوه، اخراجت ميکنن
Yeah.
آره
It's all right - you can put all your troubles in it.
اشکال نداره، همه ي دق و دلي هات رو سرشون خالي ميکني
'Ey, I lost me bag.
من ساکم رو م کردم
Yeah, I noticed. Where is it?
آره، متوجه شدم. کجاست؟
I don't know. It's lost.
نميدونم، م شده
Any valuables?
جيز با ارزشي توش بود؟
Yeah, it's got me collection of famous retired glove-puppets in there.
آره، کلکسيون دستکش هاي عروسکيم توش بود
That's it - all gone.
همين، همه اش از دست رفت
Did you get it nicked?
دزديده بوديش؟
Would you put that out?
ميشه اون رو ببري بيرون؟
I 'an't cleaned me teeth yet
من هنوز دندون هام رو نشستم
Could you not just put 'em in a glass or something, no?
نميتوني توي ليواني، يزي، بذاريشون؟
I remember when you bought these shorts. I warned you
يادمه که کي اين زيرشلواري رو خريدي. من بهت
about 'em then.
در موردش هشدار دادم
Yeah, well,
آره خب
I only got them to piss you off
من فقط براي اينکه برينم به تو رفتمش
Mission accomplished.
ماموريت انجام شد
Is he all right?
حالش خوبه؟
Yeah
آره
What is this, a spectator sport or something?
اين کارها معنيش يه؟ ورزش تماشاران؟
The hundred-metre vomit.
صد متر استفراغ
Sophie, d'you mind if I 'ave a word
سوفي ناراحت نميشي اه بخوام تنهايي
with Johnny on me own?
با جاني صحبت کنم؟
D'you want a word with Louise on your own?
ميخواي تنهايي با لوئيس صحبت کني؟
Are you bein' sarcastic?
داري مسخره بازي در مياري؟
No
نه
Well, do as you're told.
س همون کاري رو که بهت ميه بکن
Right...
باشه
Whose is all this money?
اين ولها براي کيه؟
Three hundred and eighty pounds,
سيصد و هشتاد وند
it's really oughtn't to be left laying waiting for ...
واقعا نبايد روي زمين بي افته به انتظار
Whose is all that?
براي کيه؟
Dunno
نميدونم
Who's been playing ping-pong with your face?
کي با صورتت ين ن بازي کرده؟
The sky fell in on me. A cloud caught me across the cheek.
آسمون خودش رو انداخت رو من؛ يک ابر من رو از لهام نه داشت
So, why did you come to London?
خب، براي ي اومدي لندن؟
I come to run in the Marathon
اومدم تو مسابقات ماراتون شرکت کنم
Will you give me a straight answer, please?
ميشه لطفا درست جواب من رو بدي؟
Well, I 'ad to get out of Manchester
خب، بايد از منستر ميومدم بيرون
'cos I was gonna get a beatin'
به خاطر اينکه کتک ميخوردم
And I come down 'ere, and I get a beatin'
و اومدم اينجا و کتک خوردم
Were you asking for it?
خودت خواستي؟
No.
نه
I wasn't. They just came out of nowhere.
من نخواستم. نفهميدم از کجا يداشون شد
Honest?
واقعا؟
Yeah.
آره
So what are you gonna do?
خب، ي کار مي خواهي بکني؟
What are you gonna do?
تو ي کار مي خواهي بکني؟
Dunno. Might go 'ome for the weekend.
نميدونم، شايد براي تعطيلات آخر هفته برم خونه
Well, there's no place like it.
هي جا مثل خونه نميشه
Might not come back.
شايد ديه بر نردم
Are you goin' back?
تو بر ميردي؟
Is that nice?
حال ميده؟
Yeah.
آره
I'm puttin' the fun back in 'fundament'.
من دارم سررمي رو در بنياد تو جاي ميدم
Are yer?
واقعا؟
Well, I'll 'ave to go back sometime, won't I?
خب، من هم بايد بالاخره يه وقتي برردم، نه؟
And what about us?
و ما ي؟
What about us?
ما ي؟
Do you hate me?
تو از من متنفري؟
Fuck off!
خفه شو
My mam was seven years younger than you when she had me.
مامانم هفت سال از تو کوکتر بود وقتي من رو زاييد
- Don't. - What?
نه ي؟
Just...
فقط
Well, she was!
خب، واقعا اينطوري بود
I'm full o' shit, aren't I?
مزخرف ميم، نه؟
Sometimes
اهي
Yeah, well, it's all right, I've had it all kicked out of me now
آره، خب، اشکال نداره، من بايد اين يزها رو از خودم بيرون بريزم
Oh? Good
اوه، خوبه
What if God just put us 'ere for his own entertainment?
اه خدا ما رو فقط براي سررميش اينجا ذاشته باشه ي؟
That's all we are. Just somethin' for 'im to 'ave
تمام يزي که ما هستيم همينه فقط يزهايي براي اون که داشته باشدشون
a bit of a laugh at. Could be, couln'n't it?
يکم مسخره است. نه؟
If you think about it.
اه يکم بهش فکر کني
Give us your right 'and.
دست راستت رو بده
Other way up.
از اون طرف
What's that?
اين يه؟
That's funny to me
خيلي بامزست
You're daft, you
تو ديوونه اي
It's toilet humor
شوخي توالتي
Will you give me a cuddle,
من رو بقلم ميکني
Johnny?
جاني؟
Yeah.
آره
If no one tells me what's going on, then how am I supposed -
اه کسي به من نه که اينجا ه خبره من طوري
I don't understand, Johnny!
من نميفهمم جاني
- 'Ow was Zambia? - It was Zimbabwe!
زامبيا طور بود؟ اون زيمباوه بود
I went to Zimbabwe with my wanker boyfriend, my ex...
من رفته بودم زيمباوه با دوست سر جلقيم
What did I do wrong?
ه کار خطايي از من سر زد؟
Did you see any big animals?
حيوانات عظيم الجثه رو هم ديدي؟
Yes! We saw elephants and rhinos and zebras
آره، ما فيل و کردن و ورخر
and lions and vultures...
و شير و کفتار ديديدم
Did you see any monkeys?
ميمون هم ديدين؟
We saw many monkeys.
يک عالمه ميمون ديديم
And were they cheeky? Oh, it is not good for me, is it, all this, in my condition?
ررو بودن؟ اوه، اين براي من خوب نيست، تمام اينا با اين وضع من
Well, yes, no, yes...
خب، آره، نه، آره
It's not good for me. It's not good for you. It's not good for any of us, it's utterly...
براي من خوب نيست، برا تو خوب نيست براي هي کدوم از ما خوب نيست، فقط
Oh, excuse me for living!
اوه، من رو به خاطر زنده بودنم ببخشيد
Is, is this it, Johnny?
اينه، جاني؟
- Is it? - Is what it?
اينه؟ ي اينه؟
Oh, I can't bear it!
اوه، من ديه تحملش رو ندارم
Right! I'm off!
من ميرم
Off your trolley.
مدونت رو هم با خودت ببر
Oh, don't fuckin' take a piss out of me you bastard!!
اه، انقدر به من نرين حرومزاده
You don't know!
تو درک نميکني
All I want...
من فقط ميخوام
Nobody has any...
کسي
Can you just please try...
ميشه لطفا سعي کنين
I've 'ad enough.
من بسمه
This is a nightmare!
اين يک کابوسه
Sophie, if you just try and pull yourself together
سوفي، اه فقط سعي کنين باهم همکاري کنين
- Where are you going? - I don't know
کجا ميري؟ نميدونم
Why don't you come in and have a lie-down?
را نمياي تو دراز بکشي؟
I don't care!
نميخوام
Sophie!
سوفي
- Here's the key - Well, I don't wan' 'em!
اينم کليدا خب، من نميخوامشون
Well I don't fuckin' want them!
خب، منم نميخوامشون
I'm not a social worker!
من سرکارر نيستم
Look, Sophie. Don't be fuckin' stupid!
ببين، سوفي. احمق نباش
What's the point, Louise?
که ي بشه لوئيس؟
Sophie!
سوفي
I'm sorry
من متاسفم
Johnny
جاني
You all right?
حالت خوبه؟
I'm goin'
من ميرم
Where?
کجا؟
Work. To 'and my notice in.
سر کار. که اطلاع بدم
Then I'm comin' back 'ere, I'm packing me bags,
بعد برميردم اينجا و مدون هام رو ميبندم
and I'm goin' 'ome.  D'you wanna come?
و ميرم خونه. تو هم ميخواي بياي؟
- Today? - Yeah.
امروز؟ آره
- Are you serious?
جدي ميي؟
- 'Ow? - Bus.
طوري؟ با اتوبوس
- Well, 'ave you got enough dough? - Yeah.
ول به اندازه ي کافي داري؟ آره
- 'Cos I've not got nothin' - I know.
ون من هيي ندارم ميدونم
D'you think you can make it?
فکر ميکني بتوني؟
Don't know.
نميدونم
Well, if you dpn't, we can stay 'ere until tomorrow.
خب، اه نميتوني، ما ميتونيم تا فردا اينجا بمونيم
See you later.
ميبينمت
Can you leave us a few fags for cancer research?
ميتوني براي تحقيقات سرطان ندتا سيار بدي؟
Here are your...
بيا
I was actually hoping that the air could...
من واقعا اميدوارم که هوا
What are we gonna do about all this...
ما بايد با اينها ي کار کنيم؟
I dunno, Sandra. Look, I'll see you in a couple of hours.
نميدونم ساندرا ببين، من ند ساعت ديه ميبينمت
Fine.
خوبه
You will come back?
برميردي؟
Yeah, of course I will
آره، البته که اين کار رو ميکنم
Because I need...
ونکه من نياز دارم به
You'll be all right, won't you?
خوب ميشي، نه؟
Will I be all right, love?
من خوب ميشم عزيزم؟
I'm going to get the bath cleaned.
من ميرم که حموم رو تميز کنم
You all know what it does to you
شما همتون ميدونين که اين ه بلايي سرتون مياره
and yet you still insist on doing it, so... do it.
و همنان اصرار دارين که بهش ادامه بدين، خب... ادامه بدين
Smoke yourself to...
دود کنين خودتون رو به
Well, birds do it, bees do it.
خب، رنده ها اين کار رو ميکنن زنبور ها ميکنن
..high heaven.
فراز آسمان
Can you tell me something, love?
ميتوني يک يزي به من بي عزيزم
Is it true that some babies are born covered in fur?
اين حقيقت داره که بعضي از به ها خزه وش به دنيا ميان؟
Up.
بالا
Thank you.
مرسي
And you know at birth when they cut the umbilical cord?
و ميدوني سر زايمان ه موقع بند نافشون رو ميبرن؟
What would happen if, well, if it was never cut?
ه اتفاقي مي افته اه، خب، اه هي وقت بريده نشه؟
I don't need this. I just...
من به اينا احتياجي ندارم. من فقط
Well it would be embarrassin', wouldn't it?
خب شايد خجالت آور باشه، نه؟
Specially at my age.
مخصوصا تو سن من
Why do you feel the need to take the piss?
تو را فکر ميکني نياز داري بشاشي؟
I'm not takin' a piss. It's nice, that -
من نميشاشم اون ه جالبه
Where it is from?
مال کجاست؟
I don't know, it's something my dad...
نميدونم، اين يک يزيه که بابام
Now you see,
حالا ميبيني
Sophie just turned that to the wall, she's got
سوفي اون رو به ديوار زد، اون
this kind of an irritating proclivity for negation -
يک جور محرک تمايل براي نفي داره
I suppose she thinks it's progressive, or somethin'.
به نظر من اون فکر ميکرد اين يک هنر يشروست
What is your problem?
مشکل تو يه؟
Nothing. What is your problem?
هيي، مشکل تو يه؟
All these silly questions and...
تمام اين سوالات احمقانه و
Well, look, I've never met a nurse before, and
خب، ببين، من تا حالا هي رستاري رو نديده بودم، و
I'm just interested in, well, in life.
فقط علاقه مندم، تو زندي
I mean, d'you think it's worth savin'?
فکر ميکني اين ارزش نه داشتن داشته باشه؟
Of course I do. But there is a time and a place,
البته که داره. ولي الان تو اين زمان و اين مکان
and actually this isn't the time or...
و در واقع الان وقتش نيست يا
The place?
مکانش؟
No. And this
نه، و اين
is where I...
جاييه که
Live?
زندي ميکني؟
Yes,
آره
- and I'm not feeling very... - Sexy?
من حس نميکنم خيلي سکسي هستي؟
Comfortable, actually. I'm not feeling very comfortable.
راحت، در واقع، من خيلي احساس راحتي نميکنم
Well make yourself comfortable, love. Or slip into something more...
خب، راحت باش عزيزم. يا يک لباس راحتتر
comfortable
بوش
My bath!
حموم
Hot toast... hot milk.. hot-water bottle
تُست داغ...شير داغ. بطري آب داغ
bed, sleep.
تخت، خواب
D'you like me?
تو من رو دوست داري؟
I don't know you, so...
من تو رو نميشناسم، س
D'you find me attractive?
به نظرت من جذابم؟
Well, listen, love, it's like this - I find you attractive. Very attractive.
خب، وش کن، مثلا به نظر من تو جذابي. خيلي جذاب
Enough. I've had enough.
کافيه. من ديه بسمه
It comes at me from all angles.
از همه طرف داره مياد
You... all of you just...
شما.. همه ي شما فقط
it's the tin lid...
يک دروش حلبي
When... how will the world ever...
کي... طوري دنيا
End.
به ايان ميرسه؟
Yes!
آره
Adaptation : McFist & Wild Arrowroot, 2005
mehdipourfar@gmail.com